(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
あずいろ食堂
Azuiro Shokudo
「こんあずー！」「こんかさまー！」「バウバウ！」
“Con-AZKi!” “Con-Kasama!” “Bau Bau!”
ということで本日は、はい、あずいろ食堂開店！
And so, today, yes, Azuiro Shokudo is now open!
「イェーイ！」「開店！」「開店！」
“Yay!” “Open!” “Open!”
そして、昨日ね、あずいろで仕込みをしたんですけれども、終わりました。
And we did the prep work for Azuiro yesterday, and it's all done.
今日フワモコちゃんにも来ていただいて、お給仕していただきます！
Today, Fuwamoco-chan is here to help us serve!
「イェーイ！」「お給仕！」「お給仕！」
“Yay!” “Serving!” “Serving!”
ということで、あのちょっと早速、ちょっとあの事件が発生してましてですね、
And so, actually, something's already happening...
開店前から並んでるお客様が数名いらっしゃいまして。もういるんですね。
...several customers have been lining up since before we opened. They're already here.
「じゃああの、お尻が前組から…」「お、オッケー。あ、言い方w」
“So, starting with those whose... 'rear' is at the front?” “Okay, okay. Way to put it lol.”
第1号のお客様、いらっしゃいませ！
Our first customer, welcome!
「いらっしゃいませ！」「いらっしゃいませ！」
“Welcome!” “Welcome!”
The first customer is somebody, somebody!
「誰かな？」「誰かな？」
“Who could it be?” “Who could it be?”
誰かな？ You ready, you ready...
Who could it be? You ready, you ready...
もう声入ってますよ。
We can already hear your voice.
本日のお客様
Today's Customers
自己紹介から、ね。
Start with an introduction, please.
自己紹介から、どっち？どっちから？
Starting with an introduction, which one? Which one first?
はーい！あ、あ、シシリアてです。シシリ人間、大感謝！大感謝！やった、やった！
Hi! Uh, I'm Cecilia-te. Shishiri human, so thankful! So thankful! Yay, yay!
「そして、」「アキモーニ、あきです。」
“And,” “Aki-morning, I'm Aki.”
やったー！
Yay!
そして、えー、祭りです。
And, uh, it's Matsuri.
神！神だよ、神！
God! I'm God, God!
第一のお客様として、開店前から並んでいただいておりました。
As our first customers, they've been lining up since before we opened.
10分前ぐらいから並んでた。
I've been waiting for about 10 minutes.
あ、祭り先輩、顔出してる。コメント見て、あ、後ろにいるじゃんって。
Oh, Matsuri-senpai is showing her face. I looked at the comments and was like,
「後ろにいるじゃん」って言ってるじゃんw
“Oh, she's right behind us!” lol.
ということで、今日はですね、画面見てる皆さん、こちらにお品書きがあるんですが、
And so, for everyone watching, we have the menu here...
今日あの、配膳係という名前の手は風真いろはです。こちらですね。
...today, the one acting as the 'serving staff' is me, Kazama Iroha. Right here.
ちょっと上から読み上げますね。おでんが、大根、卵、こんにゃく、ちくわ、昆布、
I'll read them from the top. For the oden, we have: daikon, egg, konjac, chikuwa, kombu,
さつま揚げ、はんぺん、もち巾着、牛すじ、
satsuma-age, hanpen, mochi-kinchaku, beef tendon,
あとウインナー巻きとうずら巻きとロールキャベツがあるんですが、こちらは数が少ないです。
and we also have sausage rolls, quail egg rolls, and cabbage rolls, but we have limited quantities of those.
オーケー。あ、美味しそう。
Okay. Oh, looks delicious.
合わせで、他が唐揚げと、え、風真家の梅干しおにぎりと、
Along with that, we have fried chicken, and Kazama family's pickled plum rice balls,
毎度おなじみ風真いろはのござるクッキー、そしてロールキャベツコンソメ味が限定でございます。あります。はい。
and the usual Kazama Iroha “Gozaru Cookies”. Also, we have a limited supply of consomme-flavored cabbage rolls. Yes.
ということで、じゃあおでんは... 食べたいぞ、ちょっと見つけられるかわかんないぞ...
So, the oden is ready and waiting... “I want to eat it!” but I'm not sure if I can find it...
ですが、じゃあ祭り先輩から。何？
...well, starting with Matsuri-senpai. What would you like?
「大根と…」「大根下の方に入ってるよ。」
“Daikon and...” “The daikon is at the bottom.”
「卵と…」「卵も下の方に入ってるよ。」
“Egg and...” “The egg is also at the bottom.”
えーと、ちくわと、もち巾着と、牛すじと、
Um, chikuwa, mochi-kinchaku, and beef tendon,
めっちゃ食べてくれる！
You're eating a lot!
「ウインナー巻きと、もち巾着ここ…」「もちもち、もちもち。」
“Sausage roll, and mochi-kinchaku here...” “Mochi mochi, mochi mochi.”
牛すじ、牛すじ、牛すじ... あ、昆布行ってない。オーケー、オーケー。
Beef tendon, beef tendon, beef tendon... oh, I didn't say kombu. Okay, okay.
優しく、優しく。実はフワモコちゃん、おでんまだ見た目と名前が一致してないものもあるそうなので、
Gently, gently. Actually, Fuwamoco-chan says she can't quite match all the oden names to their appearances yet...
牛すじ、牛すじ、牛すじちっちゃい。多分ね、落ちてる鍋の中に。
...beef tendon, beef tendon, the beef tendon is tiny. It probably fell into the pot.
ちょっと頑張って今日覚えて...
I'll try my best to remember today...
ダイコンやってます!
We're doing Daikon!
Cookies!
これ食べていいクッキーなの?
Are these cookies okay to eat?
あ、それお皿に開けてもらっていいですか?
Ah, could you put those on a plate?
はい!
Yes!
Cookies!
Eat cookies! Yummy!
Yummy yummy yummy...
Eat cookies! Everyone!
え、おいしそう!
Whoa, it looks delicious!
クッキー!
Cookie!
あとは、ロールキャベツはいかがですか?
And how about some cabbage rolls?
沈んでるから...
They're sunken...
ウィンナー巻き、発見できるかな?
Can we find the wiener rolls?
ウィンナー巻き!
Wiener rolls!
もしかしたら沈んでるから、探してみてください。
They might be at the bottom, so please look for them.
Delicious!
あ、ウィンナー巻きこれだね。
Ah, here's a wiener roll.
それだね!
That's it!
これ、えっとさつま揚げ?
This is, uh, satsuma-age?
あ、さつま揚げ!
Ah, satsuma-age!
もう一個持ってる?
Do you have one more?
さつま揚げ...
Satsuma-age...
これもさつま揚げじゃない?
Isn't this also satsuma-age?
これか! これです、これ。
This one! It's this one, this.
あ、餅巾着!
Ah, mochi-kinchaku!
じゃあ、みんな、これで完成!
Okay everyone, it's done!
完成!
Done!
じゃあ、こちらを、出そう!
Now, let's serve this!
じゃあ、こちらがご注文のお品書きになります。
Now, here is the ordered dish.
じゃあ、これをギギちゃんにお渡しになります。
Now, we'll hand this to Gigi-chan.
おかわりもあるぞ! おかわりも!
Second helpings too! Second helpings!
Eat up!
Satsuma-age, yummy!
Yummy!
Choice oden?
あ、そっち唐揚げを今...
Ah, over there, the karaage now...
唐揚げ!
Karaage!
唐揚げも食べてください。
Please eat the karaage too.
エンちゃんとラオーラ先輩、お待たせいたしました。
En-chan and Raora-senpai, sorry to keep you waiting.
お待たせいたしました。
Sorry to keep you waiting.
お待たせ!
Here you go!
今日は実は先にフワモコに食べてもらった...
Actually, we had Fuwamoco eat first today...
Eat up, eat up!
美味しかったやつを全部入れましょう。
Let's put in everything that was delicious.
Oh, yummy!
美味しいやつ!
The yummy ones!
Are you hungry?
Yes, I'm hungry!
I'm so hungry!
Hungry, hungry!
I could eat a horse!
A what?!
You could eat a horse!
Eat a horse?
Horse! Horse!
ギギちゃんが食べたことない、おでん!
Gigi-chan has never eaten oden!
Yeah!
Okay, let's try.
はんぺんがすごい美味しかったから...
The hanpen was really delicious, so...
はんぺんはマスト!
Hanpen is a must!
はんぺんマストだね。
Hanpen is a must, yeah.
あとチクワも大好き。
And I love chikuwa too.
ギギちゃんとセシリアちゃん、おでん食べるの初めて?
Gigi-chan and Cecilia-chan, is this your first time eating oden?
First time!
Oh, first time here!
Ever!
あ、セシリアちゃん、人生初?
Ah, Cecilia-chan, first time in your life?
人生初!
First time in my life!
人生初おでん!
First oden of your life!
じゃあ、餅巾着にしよう。
Then, let's go with mochi-kinchaku.
あずいろが作ったおでん...
The oden Azuiro made...
セシリア、餅巾着見たことない!
Cecilia has never seen mochi-kinchaku!
Wow!
嬉しい!
I'm happy!
初があずいろおでん?
First time is Azuiro oden?
え、嬉しい! 人生初。
Eh, I'm happy! First time in your life.
Yummy oden for the first time!
Konjac, konjac, must!
Konjac, konjac, must have!
Hooray!
じゃあ、いこう。
Okay, let's go.
じゃあ、いける?
Okay, ready?
やったー!
Yay!
あ、だけど、ウィンナー巻きフワモコ食べてない。
Ah, but Fuwamoco hasn't eaten the wiener roll.
ちょうど一個!
Exactly one left!
クッキーだけまだ...
Only cookies yet...
あ、クッキー。
Ah, cookies.
じゃあ、みんなで、いただきます?
Then, shall we all say 'itadakimasu'?
いただきます!
Itadakimasu!
Cookies, yummy!
Oh, yummy!
よかった、よかった。
Good, good.
職人さんが朝からやってますから。
Because the artisan has been at it since morning.
Artisan?
これ、いいの?
Is this okay?
オッケー、ヤミー!
Okay, yummy!
大丈夫そう?
Does it seem okay?
じゃあ、ギギちゃんのはお箸...
Now, Gigi-chan's chopsticks...
ギギちゃんのは、何入れようかな。
For Gigi-chan's, what should I put in?
ギギちゃん、はんぺん?
Gigi-chan, hanpen?
あ、オッケー。
Ah, okay.
ありがとうございます!
Thank you!
じゃあ、ギギちゃんにはさつま揚げとイワシつみれ...
Then, for Gigi-chan, satsuma-age and sardine fish ball...
卵も!
Egg too!
卵もすごい!
The eggs are great too!
Mochi-kinchaku, yummy!
暑い! Too hot!
Hot! Too hot!
暑い、暑い!
Hot, hot!
Be careful! Especially the eggs!
The eggs are probably going to be really hot on the inside, so be careful not to burn your mouth, Gigi.
お箸はどこ?
Where are the chopsticks?
フワモコが、お箸係...
Fuwamoco is the chopstick person...
ね、もちろん!
Right, of course!
どきどきしながら店主の顔しとくね。
I'll keep my 'shop owner' face on while feeling nervous.
Cecilia can not... so hungry.
Cecilia can't eat that much.
あ、これでもういいんじゃない?
Ah, isn't this enough then?
もう一個、でも餅巾着も食べてほしい。
One more... but I want you to eat the mochi-kinchaku too.
セシリア、餅巾着、you like it?
Cecilia, mochi-kinchaku, you like it?
かわいい!
Cute!
Can you share with Gigi?
And Elizabeth?
Oh, okay. Let's try... one.
Gigi with sharing?
Gigi is sharing?
オッケー、じゃあ、何個か具材を選んで...
Okay, so, choose a few ingredients...
いただくということで。
And we'll serve them.
じゃあ、セシリアの...
Now, Cecilia's...
卵、こんにゃく、大根!
Egg, konjac, daikon!
美味しい!
Delicious!
あとさつま揚げ、ちくわ。あ、餅巾着も!
And satsuma-age, chikuwa. Oh, and mochi-kinchaku too!
Daikon, yummy! Konjac!
Konjac!
And then the colorful one,
the purpley-looking one.
うわぁ！いただきます！
Whoa! Let's eat!
1、2、3、4...
1, 2, 3, 4...
Karaage, yes please. いただきます。
Karaage, yes please. Let's eat.
1つ、2つ... 2つで。
One, two... two pieces, please.
Yeah, yeah, We're having this!
食べます？
Are you eating?
Yeah, yeah, 食べます！
Yeah, yeah, we're eating!
いただきます！AZKi先輩が...
Let's eat! AZKi-senpai is...
...取り分け係をしてくれてます。
...acting as the server for us.
Karaage, one please.
Karaage, yes please.
Karaage too, okay? Yeah!
For me? ありがとうござる、ジジ。
For me? Thank you, Gigi-gozaru.
助かる。うまい！
That helps. Delicious!
いただきます！
Let's eat!
おっばたー！
Ooppataa!
さあ、おでん。おでんからいただくか。
Now, the oden. Let's start with the oden.
「好き」って言ってくれたござるからな。
Since you said you liked it, Gozaru.
あーん。
Ahn.
どうぞ、召し上がれ！Eat up!
Please, help yourself! Eat up!
おおっ！唐揚げ！
Ooh! Karaage!
すごく美味しいよね！It's so delicious!
It's so delicious! It's so delicious!
めっちゃ美味しい！
It's super delicious!
良かった。染み染みだ。
I'm glad. It's really soaked in flavor.
Did you have the egg?
It's so soft. 卵、soft、ふわふわ。
It's so soft. The egg is soft and fluffy.
あ、柔らかい、ふわふわ！
Ah, so soft and fluffy!
ふわふわ、卵ふわふわ！
Fluffy, the egg is so fluffy!
日本語上手で嬉しい！
I'm so happy your Japanese is so good!
ござるおじさん、嬉しくなっちゃった。
Gozaru-uncle is getting happy.
ござるおじさん？
Gozaru-uncle?
すごい、なんかござる... ござる泣き。
Wow, some kind of... Gozaru-crying.
昆布もね、ちょっと、そう。
And the kelp too, yeah.
昆布好きなのかな？
I wonder if they like kelp?
やる友子（こ）は... 昆布好きなの？
Do the Yarutomo-ko... like kelp?
昆布美味しいって言う時もありますけど...
There are times when they say it's delicious, but...
...ちょっと今日は昆布ちょっと苦手っていう時もあるから。
...there are also times when they aren't feeling kelp.
なんか「昆布茶（こんぶちゃ）」もあるんですよね。
There's also 'Konbu-cha', right?
なんか「昆布茶」もある。そうだけどなんか...
There's also 'Konbu-cha'. That's true, but...
...海外の「Kombucha」とかもあって。
...there's also the Western 'Kombucha'.
そうだね。違うね。
That's right. It's different.
Kombuchaと、昆布茶、Kombucha。
Kombucha and Konbu-cha, Kombucha.
Kombucha? 昆布茶か。
Kombucha? Ah, Konbu-cha.
Overseas Kombucha is different.
そう、そう。
Yes, exactly.
この昆布は大丈夫。
This kelp is fine.
大丈夫。今日食べてないからちょっと気になる。
It's fine. I haven't had any today, so I'm curious.
おい、食べる？
Hey, want some?
食べる、食べる！うずら巻きもちょっと...
Yes, yes! Try some of the quail egg roll too...
...食べてみて、AZKi先輩。
...please try it, AZKi-senpai.
はい！なに？
Okay! What's this?
ちくわ巻き？
Chikuwa roll?
Oh, fish cake! Fish cake!
あぁ！練り物って... うまい、美味しい！
Ah! These fish pastes... are so good, delicious!
確かに、「練り物」って英語でなんて言うの？
By the way, how do you say 'nerimono' in English?
Fish... fish paste?
Fish paste... fish paste? Fish piece?
みたいな感じ？ So, paste?
Something like that? So, paste?
Yeah, fish paste.
What do you think? It's yummy, 美味しい！
What do you think? It's yummy, delicious!
美味しい！良かった〜。
Delicious! I'm so glad.
こんなに「美味しい」って言われて救われた。
I feel so vindicated having you say it's delicious.
今日これだけで救われてるよ。
This alone makes today worth it.
Cooking 天才！やった！
Cooking genius! Yay!
本当に美味しいよね。美味しい。
It really is delicious. Delicious.
ござるおじさん泣いちゃうよ。
Gozaru-uncle is going to cry.
あとおにぎりもあるんで、一緒にどうぞ。
We also have onigiri, so please have some.
あの、うちの... スポンサーが... スポンサーって名前の...
Well, my... sponsor... under the name of 'sponsor'...
...うちの実家が色々用意してくれてた。
...my family back home prepared a lot for us.
スポンサーという名前の私の家の仕送りで...
From the care package my home sent under the name 'sponsor'...
...作ったおにぎりなんで。
...I made these rice balls.
梅干しはござるが漬けました。
I pickled the plums myself, Gozaru.
梅干し漬けてくれてる！すご！
You pickled them yourself! Amazing!
梅干しだけござるが。
Just the plums, by Gozaru.
そして今日ですね、この「あずいろ食堂」開店祝いの...
And today, to celebrate the opening of 'Azu-Iro Diner'...
...フラスタをいただきました！
...we received flower stands!
わぁ！お見せしたい！Wow!
Whoa! I want to show them! Wow!
ちょっと見てほしい、みんなに。
I want everyone to see them.
見てみたい！フラスタ？
I want to see! Flower stands?
ちょっと見てもらっていいですか？
Could you take a look at them?
あ、すごい！わぁぁ！すごい、おめでとう！
Ah, wow! Waaah! Amazing, congratulations!
あの、昨日の制作配信、クッキング配信で...
Well, during yesterday's prep stream, the cooking stream...
...ござるが「じゃあフラスタ送りたい人はピンクでよろしく」...
...I said, 'If you want to send flowers, please make them pink'...
...って言ったらこんなことになってしまいました。
...and this happened.
開店祝いありがとうございます！
Thank you for the opening celebration!
気軽に言ってごめん！ありがとうみんな！
Sorry for mentioning it so casually! Thank you everyone!
本当にこんなにフラスタ送られてくると思わなかったんだ。
I really didn't think so many flower stands would be sent.
許してくれ！ありがとうございます！
Forgive me! Thank you very much!
すごい本当に。凄いんだよね。
It's really amazing. They're incredible.
うずら巻き？これうずら巻きかな？
Quail egg roll? Is this a quail egg roll?
あ、いわし団子？
Ah, sardine balls?
いわし団子は食べるの忘れてた。
I forgot to eat the sardine balls.
いわし団子は sardines? Fish?
Sardine balls are sardines? Fish?
あ、そうなんだ！へ〜、気になる！
Ah, is that so! Hmm, I'm curious!
後で食べたい。
I want to eat them later.
つみれはでも大人の味じゃない？
Aren't fish balls an 'adult' taste though?
つみれ、ちょっと大人の味が... 美味しい。
Fish balls have a bit of an adult taste... Delicious.
二人はおでん何が好き？魚じゃない？
What do you two like in oden? Isn't it fish?
私は昆布が好きなんですよ。
I really like the kombu (kelp).
あの、くたくたの昆布。
You know, the really soft, chewy kind.
大人だな。
How sophisticated.
やわらかーい。
It's so soft.
私は大根かな、やっぱり。
I guess I like daikon (radish) the best, after all.
いいですね。
That's a good one.
ござるさんは？
How about you, Gozaru-san?
いろはは、子供の頃は、母親と卵を奪い合いました。
As a child, I used to fight with my mom over the eggs.
あー、卵美味しい。
Ah, eggs are delicious.
卵を取り合いました。
We really fought for them.
エッグ、おいしい！
Eggs are delicious!
まつり先輩は何が好きですか？おでんは。
Matsuri-senpai, what do you like in your oden?
もち巾着！
Mochi kinchaku!
もち巾着！おいしいー！
Mochi kinchaku! So good!
Rice cake! Stretch and chewy!
Rice cake! Stretchy and chewy!
I like it! I like it! So delicious!
That's my favorite one.
And the hanpen too. What do you think of the hanpen?
What's the hanpen?
What's hanpen?
That's what you're eating.
おいしい！おいしい！
Delicious! Delicious!
It's really yummy! And the texture!
And the kombu seaweed, it's really good too. It has a lot of flavor, umami.
And the kombu seaweed is really good too. It has a lot of flavor, umami.
Umami! Umami!
I really like the egg.
You like it? Egg, yeah! 好き！
You like it? Egg, yeah! I love it!
Texture!
The texture!
あー、食感、食感ですね。
Ah, the texture, right.
確かに、ふわふわ。
It's definitely fluffy.
はんぺんは、はんぺんで伝わらないよね。
'Hanpen' doesn't really translate as is, does it?
Fish cake. Everything is fish cake.
Fish cake. Everything is a fish cake.
あ、そうなんだ。練り物はまとめてフィッシュケーキなんだ。
Oh, I see. All paste products are grouped as 'fish cake'.
いっぱい種類があるけどね。
Even though there are so many varieties.
わかめも？
Wakame too?
Wakame seaweed.
Kombu seaweed.
あ、そうなるんだね。
Ah, so that's how they're called.
Enoki mushroom.
これが文化の違いか。
I guess this is the cultural difference.
And what do you think of the soup? Dashi?
And what do you think of the soup? The dashi?
おいしい！おいしい！ It's been cooked overnight.
Delicious! Delicious! It's been cooked overnight.
めちゃめちゃフレーバー。
So much flavor.
A lot of flavor!
フレーバー？味？
Flavor? You mean the taste?
めちゃめちゃ味！味！
Lots of taste! Taste!
今日は鰹...
Today, I used bonito...
めんつゆちょっと...
...a little bit of mentsuyu...
あと白だし、昆布、昆布。
...and white dashi and kombu seaweed.
Kombu seaweed, white dashi stock...
Mentsuyu...
他になにか入れたっけ？
Was there anything else I put in?
でも朝仕込んだのは、それだけだね。
Well, that's everything we prepared this morning.
あとは全部具材の旨味だね。
The rest is all just the umami from the ingredients.
What's in it? And the mochi!
Mochi! Mochi! Mochi!
Eating from the top, the mochi's at the bottom.
I'm a mess! おいしい！
I'm a mess! It's so good!
熱そう！めちゃめちゃ伸びてる！
It looks hot! It's stretching so much!
見てるー！
I see it!
うわー！すごい！
Whoa! That's amazing!
ござる驚愕してるよ。結構減ってない？
I'm in shock. Hasn't it decreased quite a bit?
まつり先輩、結構食べてる。
Matsuri-senpai is eating a lot.
おかわり！
Refill!
でもまだ来るかもしれないから。
But more people might still come.
来ないとも限らないからね。
We can't be sure they won't.
いっぱい食べてほしい。
I want you to eat plenty.
今日はクリスマスと違って、みんなスタジオに...
Today, unlike Christmas, everyone is here in the studio.
嬉しい、来てくれて。
I'm so glad you came.
ジジちゃん食べなくて大丈夫？
Gigi-chan, are you okay not eating more?
さっき食べたし、今日は朝ご飯に食べた。
I ate earlier, and I had some for breakfast today too.
我々は朝ご飯、おでんでした。
We had oden for breakfast.
ちょっと味見がてらね。
Just a little taste, then.
I really like the mochi!
Mochi! おいしい！AZKi先輩！
Mochi! So good! AZKi-senpai!
Gigi-chan, baby! She can't eat!
Gigi-chan, you baby! She can't eat!
顔に付いてる！
It's on your face!
Messy baby!
Cute!
ジジちゃんとセシリアちゃんは、この凸待ち自体が...
For Gigi-chan and Cecilia-chan, this call-in stream...
そう、初めてです！
...yes, it's our first time!
First time coming to one of these!
And we got lucky, we got food! So happy, thank you!
からしとかもあったの？
Was there any karashi (mustard) too?
あります。
Yes, there is.
からし。
The mustard.
The spicy mustard that goes with it too.
からし入れてください。
Please put some mustard in.
Karashi tastes like wasabi a bit. Doesn't it?
うん、なんかワサビに似てる味がします。
Yeah, it tastes a bit like wasabi.
する？するかな？辛いのかな？
It does? Does it? Is it spicy?
ジジちゃんね、もうお腹いっぱい。
JiJi-chan is already full.
え！お腹いっぱい！
Eh! I'm full!
JiJi-chan can eat a horse! お腹いっぱい！
JiJi-chan can eat a horse! I'm full!
お腹いっぱい！お腹いっぱい！
I'm full! I'm full!
無理はしないで。
Don't push yourself.
無理しちゃうクッキー！
I'll push myself cookie!
クッキークッキークッキークッキー！
Cookie cookie cookie cookie!
モココは参りました。モココ参りました。JiJi-chan eat.
Mococo is defeated. Mococo is defeated. JiJi-chan, eat.
お、ジジちゃんまだ残ってるの？
Oh, JiJi-chan still has some left?
This still have leftovers there. お、Bau Bau!
There are still leftovers there. Oh, Bau Bau!
It's okay, I can eat it. I'll eat it for her. 優しい！
It's okay, I can eat it. I'll eat it for her. So kind!
OK! I'll Gozaru Cookie too! Yeah!
Yummy!
そっか、初めて会った時からござるクッキー美味いって。
Right, you've said Gozaru Cookies are delicious since we first met.
すごい美味しいって食べてくれて…嬉しい。
I'm happy you ate them and said they're delicious.
おでんでんきゅん！おでんでんきゅん！
Oden-den-kyun! Oden-den-kyun!
おでんでんきゅん！
Oden-den-kyun!
Thank you! You're welcome! Yeah, you're welcome!
You're not going to explain to them what it means?
No no no no! What? Nevermind!
美味しい、嬉しいよ。
Delicious, I'm happy.
やばい！ライブで見てくれるなんて。
This is bad! To think you're watching this live.
うまい！
Tasty!
（食べる音）いいよ、中身を。
(Eating sounds) It's okay, have some of the inside.
どうぞ。気をつけて。
Here you go. Be careful.
あ、でもまだいっぱいある。卵もいっぱいあるよ。
Ah, but there's still a lot. There's plenty of eggs too.
そう、だってめっちゃ作ったもん。
Yeah, because we made so much.
そう。食べたいんです。
Right. I want to eat.
Hey Miss Gozaru! Miss AZKi! 食べたいっていう顔付きできていいですよ。
Hey Miss Gozaru! Miss AZKi! You've come with a face that says "I want to eat".
あと10分だけ待ってやれ！あと10分だけ待ってやれ！
Wait just 10 more minutes! Wait just 10 more minutes!
（笑い声）全然いいよ。
(Laughing) That's totally fine.
10分だけ待ったっていい。10分だけ待ってくれる？
It's okay to wait just 10 minutes. Can you wait just 10 minutes?
なんかおまじないかけた方が良かったかなって思う。
I think it might have been better to cast a spell on it.
おまじない！あ、確かに！やってもらおう！
A spell! Ah, for sure! Let's have them do it!
おでんおでんきゅん！おでんおでんきゅん！
Oden oden kyun! Oden oden kyun!
おでんくん！おでんおでんきゅん！AZKiさんもやってくれる。なんかはんぺんの形で。
Oden-kun! Oden oden kyun! AZKi-san will do it too. Like the shape of a hanpen.
はんぺんの形で！おでんおでんきゅん！可愛い！
Hanpen shape! Oden oden kyun! Cute!
Merci! It's not on all meals though!
Thank you! It's not on all meals though!
え！もう一回？You want to get the cute oden kyun?
Eh! One more time? You want to get the cute oden kyun?
You want to get the cute oden kyun? OK, OK!
あ、あ、あ、あ...
Ah, ah, ah, ah...
や、やるんだね。カメラマンくんも！
Ah, you're going to do it. Cameraman-kun too!
皆さんお願いします！OK, OK! Here we go!
Everyone, please join in! OK, OK! Here we go!
Wait, wait, AZKi-senpai! OK, OK!
おでんくん、なれ！おでんおでんきゅん！
Oden-kun, become! Oden oden kyun!
（歓声）O-pop-py! ちゃんとやった！
(Cheers) O-pop-py! We did it properly!
いろはちゃんもちゃんとやったね。やってしまった。ありがとう。
Iroha-chan did it properly too. I did it. Thank you.
おでんおでんきゅん！はんぺんの形だった。おでんおでんきゅん！
Oden oden kyun! It was in the shape of a hanpen. Oden oden kyun!
これが一番うまい出汁だろ！ああ、おでん出汁美味しい。
This must be the best dashi! Ah, the oden dashi is delicious.
お出汁美味しい。出汁でもまた無し。これをお願いできない？
The dashi is delicious. Dashi but no more. Can't we ask for this?
おでんおでんきゅん！ご来場記念おでん。
Oden oden kyun! Commemorative oden for visiting.
これをセットとして買ってくれないか？ボイス付き！
Won't you buy this as a set? With a voice!
ボイス付きで！エキスポで？エキスポで！
With a voice! At EXPO? At EXPO!
エキスポでなんて。やってほしい！
At EXPO or something. I want you to do it!
ボイス付きおでんおでんきゅんボイス！おでんおでんきゅんボイス。
Oden oden kyun voice with a voice set! Oden oden kyun voice.
ボイス付きQRコードカードかな？聞き出したら美味しくなる。
Maybe a QR code card with the voice? It'll become delicious once you listen to it.
美味しくなるやつ。今からやらないかな？
The kind that makes it delicious. Shall we do it now?
もう来月はちょっと間に合わないかな。流石に無理かな。
It might not make it in time for next month. As expected, it might be impossible.
来年！来年やってくれ。頼む。あずいろもやってよ。
Next year! Please do it next year. I beg you. Azu-Iro should do it too.
そう、あずいろふーふーしてよ。
Yeah, Azu-Iro do the "fufu".
（可愛い声）違うボイスが入ってる！
(Cute voices) A different voice is in there!
ランダムだ。ランダムボイス。モココボイスはちょっと...
It's random. Random voice. Mococo's voice is a bit...
この辺でやっちゃったら失礼するから。バウボイス苦手。
If we do it here it'll be rude, so... I'm not good at "Bau" voices.
や、確かにちょっと夢広がるなやっぱり。
Yeah, for sure, dreams are expanding after all.
いろんな交差、みんなで集まってご飯して。
Various intersections, everyone gathering and having a meal.
作ったりするのいいよね。うん！
It's nice to make things together, isn't it? Yeah!
そっか、この間のそばもね。うん！
I see, like the soba the other day too. Yeah!
でも気づいちゃったのは、多分このうちの皆そば作ったことないです！
But what I realized is, probably no one in this house has ever made soba!
そうなんですよ！そばをどうやって作るの？
That's right! How do you make soba?
どうやって茹でるの？そば。ホロそば。Soba? You made it yourself, like you boil the noodles and everything? No.
How do you boil it? Soba. Holo Soba. Soba? You made it yourself, like you boil the noodles and everything? No.
うん... そう、茹でたことない...
Yeah... right, I've never boiled one...
本気で茹でた... あ、や、１回ある！
Really boiled... oh, no, wait, I did once!
ある！あると思う！
I have! I think I have!
ね、そばって、そばだ、スバルちゃんの...
Hey, soba, it's soba. Subaru-chan's...
ね、やっぱスバルだよね、そばと言ったら。
Yeah, it's definitely Subaru when you think of soba.
一応言っとく？言っとく？
Should we mention it? Just in case?
あの、悲しみのレス...
That sad response...
ちょっとさ、だから、ちょっと前に、あずいろ食堂ありますってね、
Well, you see, a little while ago, we announced the Azuiro Shokudo...
あの、みんなにお伝えしたんですけど、お伝えして、
...we told everyone about it, and...
1分かかんないうちにスバルちゃんから「行きます」って来て。
...within a minute, Subaru-chan said "I'll be there".
で、今日来る予定だったんだけど、ちょっと...
So, she was planned to come today, but...
ちょっとね、来られなくなっちゃって。
...well, she couldn't make it.
いや、でも、あの即レスは久々に見...
Man, but that quick reply was something else...
一番食べたそうにしてた！
She seemed the most eager to eat!
一番食べたそうにしてて...
She really seemed like she wanted to eat...
今日も、あのそばの話出てたからね、聞きたかったね。
We were talking about soba today too, so I wanted to hear it.
「本当に食べたいのに！」みたいな...
"I really want to eat it though!" she was like...
「おでん食べたかったー！」って言ってくれました。
"I wanted to eat oden!" she said.
今度また、そば会に呼んで...
Let's invite her to a soba party next time...
で、まつりちゃん、次の返信してくれた...
And Matsuri-chan gave the next reply...
早かった、スバルちゃんとまつりちゃんが「行きます」って。
It was fast. Subaru-chan and Matsuri-chan both said "I'll be there".
じじちゃんとししえちゃんに質問だけど、
What kind of food do you want to eat in Japan if it's homemade?
A question for Fuwa and Mococo,
オムライス！
Omurice!
オムライス！作って、食べてみたいなって。
Omurice! I want to make it and try it.
それこそメイド喫茶体験しよう！
In that case, let's experience a maid cafe!
自分たち厨房で！
With us in the kitchen!
ししえちゃんは？日本の...
How about Mococo? Japan's...
Homemade... お弁当！
Homemade... Bento!
お弁当、みんなのお弁当食べてみたい。
Bento, I want to try everyone's bento.
なんかお弁当作り大会とか...
Maybe like a bento-making contest...
誰のお弁当でしょう！
Guess whose bento this is!
彼女弁当！
Girlfriend bento!
誰の彼女弁当食べたいの？この中で。
Whose girlfriend bento do you want to eat? Out of everyone here.
Everyone here! 先輩たち！
Everyone here! The senpais!
まつりちゃんも？彼女弁当、まつり先輩のも。
Matsuri-chan too? A girlfriend bento, Matsuri-senpai's too.
どんなお弁当作るんだろうね。
I wonder what kind of bento she makes.
作ってあげようかな、お弁当大会あったら呼んで。
Maybe I'll make one. Call me if there's a bento contest.
時期法的にお花見めっちゃいいかも。
Timing-wise, flower viewing might be great.
お弁当会、確かにお花見ピクニック...
A bento party, definitely a flower viewing picnic...
モコちゃん作ってくれたお弁当たくさん食べた...
I ate lots of bentos Mococo made...
ちなみにその昔、ホロックスではお子様ランチ選手権というのを...
By the way, a while back in HoloX, we did an "Okosama Lunch" championship...
似てる、お子様ランチ選手権...
It's similar, the Okosama Lunch championship...
お弁当もできそうではある。
A bento version seems possible too.
They had to make an okosama lunch, kind of like kids' lunch.
And it had like omurice and stuff, so cute.
お弁当の中にオムライス入れられるしね。
You can put omurice in a bento, too.
We should all eat together and then picnic.
いいなー。お花見いいですね。
Nice. Flower viewing sounds good.
クリスマスにおでんも言って、今日がありますので。
We talked about oden at Christmas, and that's why we're here today.
クリスマスね、モコちゃんが最後にデザートで...
At Christmas, Mococo finally said for dessert...
「おでん食べたい」って。
..."I want to eat oden."
食べ物が目的で今日まで過ごしてきた...
I've lived until today just for the food...
今日おでん食べてもらって、唐揚げも準備中...
Today you're eating oden, and karaage is in preparation...
唐揚げ美味しい！
Karaage is delicious!
唐揚げどうですか？
How is the karaage?
今回大きいよね！デカい！
They're big this time, right! Huge!
まだ３つしか食べてないよ。
I've only eaten three so far.
２個しか食べてないの？
Only two?
１個シェアしました！大きいから！
I shared one! Because it's big!
「何を言っているんだ」みたいな顔してる...
She's looking at me like "What are you talking about?"...
おでんもシェアしましたから。
We shared the oden too.
シェア... まつり３つ食べたか？
Shared... Did Matsuri eat three?
まだ今日は全然食べてないです。
I haven't eaten much at all today.
ちなみにですね 今日は たくさん作ってきたんですけど...
By the way, I made a lot of oden today...
まあ クリスマスほどね 人がいるものとして 想定していないので...
But, I wasn't expecting as many people as there were at Christmas...
ああ ああ こっちにお願いします
Ah, ah, over here please.
あの 後ろで うちのスタッフが みんな控えてます
Our staff are all waiting in the back...
おでんを食べたくて
...waiting to eat some oden.
おお！ オッケー！
Oh! Okay!
オッケー！ じゃあ AZKi先輩 何がいいですか？
Okay! Then AZKi-senpai, what do you recommend?
こんにゃく
Konnyaku.
こんにゃく！ オッケー！
Konnyaku! Okay!
こんにゃく カミングアップ！
Konnyaku coming up!
こんにゃく
Konnyaku.
多分 売り切れてるものもあるので 具材によっては...
Some ingredients might be sold out, so depending on the topping...
ちょっと 控えたほうがいいですね
...we should probably keep it light.
ああ こんにゃくを！
Ah, konnyaku!
こんにゃく！ やった！ ゲット！
Konnyaku! Yay! Got it!
こんにゃく これだけ？
Just konnyaku?
悩んで 悩んで
Thinking, thinking...
シンキング... はんぺん！
Thinking... Hanpen!
はんぺん！ オッケー！ はんぺん！
Hanpen! Okay! Hanpen!
はんぺん！ はんぺん！ 一旦 二個...
Hanpen! Hanpen! For now, two pieces...
オッケー！
Okay!
こんにゃく 一つ はんぺん 一つ
One konnyaku, one hanpen.
はんぺん ちょっと 小さいけど
The hanpen is a bit small, though.
出し いっぱい... 出し いっぱいだ！
A lot of broth... lots of broth!
おお！
Oh!
おお！ サウンドフォークみたい！
Oh! It's like a tuning fork!
バウバウ！ 可愛い！ 手伝いたい！
Bau bau! So cute! I want to help!
出し いっぱい
A lot of broth.
ああ ちょうど それくらいで サンキュー！
Ah, about that much is perfect. Thank you!
オッケー！ じゃあ 一旦 出しを...
Okay! Then for now, the broth...
ちょっと フーフーして フーフーして
Wait, blow on it, blow on it.
ああ おまじない おまじない！
Ah, a magic spell, a magic spell!
ここに置きます ここに置きます
I'll put it here, I'll put it here.
ああ どうしよう 二人で持って 持って
Ah, what should we do? You two hold it, hold it.
え 持って？
Eh, hold it?
横から 横同士で せーの フーフーって
From the sides, together... one, two, hoo-hoo!
すごいこと やらせますね
You're making them do something incredible.
せーの フー！ フー！
One, two, hoo! Hoo!
おお おお！ 温かいから
Wow! Because it's warm...
これ おでん おでん きゅん！
This is Oden Oden Kyun!
食堂って こういう感じだった...
So this is what a cafeteria was like...
美味しくなーれ！ おでん おでん きゅん！
Become delicious! Oden Oden Kyun!
イエーイ！ ありがとう！ いただきますよ！
Yay! Thank you! Let's eat!
調子はどうだい？ もっと食べたいかい？
How's it going? Want to eat more?
こんな感じでいい？ お腹いっぱい
Is it okay like this? I'm full!
バウバウ！ バウバウ！ バウバウ！
Bau bau! Bau bau! Bau bau!
特別な日本語
Special Japanese.
ごめん こんな感じだった 食堂
Sorry, this is what a cafeteria was like.
サービスがいいですね
The service is great.
サービスがバウバウですね
The service is bau-mazing.
サービス精神 強いやん
Strong service spirit.
おお メイド食堂になっちゃってる
Oh, it's turned into a maid cafeteria.
今日だけ メイド喫茶
Just for today, it's a maid cafe.
喫茶... 食堂じゃなくて メイド喫茶
Cafe... Not a cafeteria, but a maid cafe.
キッス！ サービスキッス！
Kiss! Service kiss!
キッス！ お願いします！
Kiss! Please!
メイドキッスが超えている
Maid Kiss has evolved.
サービス！ サービス！ サービス！
Service! Service! Service!
私 やってないですけど
I'm not doing it, though.
おでん おでん きゅん する！ 待ってるよ！
Oden Oden Kyun! I'm waiting!
従業員に嫌がらせしないで
Don't harass our workers.
ノーキッス 3000円
No kiss, 3,000 yen.
払うよ！ 3000円 払うよ！
I'll pay! I'll pay 3,000 yen!
可愛い
So cute.
ああ 払うよ よしよしよし
Ah, I'll pay. There, there, there.
考えてる 考えてる
Thinking, thinking...
どうやって やってもらおう？
How can we get them to do it?
サービス！ サービス！
Service! Service!
何か... 何か エアキッスは？
How about... how about an air kiss?
おお！ 投げキッス！
Oh! A blow kiss!
オッケー！ 投げキッスは オッケー！
Okay! Blow kisses are okay!
大丈夫だって！ 投げキッス！
It's okay! Blow kiss!
違うんだ
That's not it.
助けて！ お巡りさーん！
Help! Police!
良いレビューを書くって伝えてくれる？
Can you tell them we'll leave a good review?
Googleのレビュー！
Google reviews!
投げキッスしてくれたら Googleのレビューを！
If you give a blow kiss, a Google review!
5つ星！
5 stars!
5つ星！ キッス！ 5つ星！
5 stars! Kiss! 5 stars!
ノーキッス 0つ星
No kiss, 0 stars.
嘘でしょ！ ちょっと待って！
No way! Wait a minute!
味で 味で 味で勝負！
Compete with flavor! Flavor!
味で勝負しよう！
Let's compete with flavor!
風味は最高！ 風味！
The flavor is the best! The flavor!
そう！ そこに一番力を入れてるんだ！
Yeah! That's what we put the most effort into!
投げキッスじゃないんだ！
It's not about the blow kisses!
まだやってるよ！
They're still doing it!
でも 次は カスタマーサービス！
But next is customer service!
サービス！
Service!
ほーびーの しゅり先輩が...
Hobby-no Shuri-senpai...
AZKi先輩来てる！ いろは先輩来てる！
AZKi-senpai is here! Iroha-senpai is here!
AZKi先輩が 具をたくさんくれたんだ
AZKi-senpai gave us lots of ingredients.
ああ 幸せ！
Ah, so happy!
次回！ 次回！
Next time! Next time!
こんにゃく へにゃ
Konnyaku... soft...
いつから ここがメイド喫茶だと錯覚していたんだ
Since when did you mistake this for a maid cafe?
ごめん おじ多くない？
Sorry, aren't there too many uncles?
この おじが多いんじゃない
It's not that there are many uncles.
心に みんな おじを飼っているの
Everyone has an uncle in their heart.
おじさんを飼ってる
Keeping an uncle inside.
こんにゃく フーフー
Blowing on konnyaku.
ふーん！
Hmm!
美味しい！ 5つ星！
Delicious! 5 stars!
ありがとう！ 5つ星！ 5つ星！
Thank you! 5 stars! 5 stars!
じゃあ おじのも ちょっとやってもらおうかな
Then I'll have the uncles do some too.
やったー！
Yay!
ちょっとやってもらえる？
Can you do it for me?
やってもらわずにはいられない。
I can't go without having it done.
That last one was really good.
The food was really good.
The flavor was all there.
They did not miss on one star.
大根食べます？
Will you eat the daikon radish?
食べよ、食べよ。
Let's eat it.
うわー、おいしそう！
Wow, it looks delicious!
ちょっとやってもらっちゃおうか。
Let's have them do it.
ふわわさんも、自分が作った料理に...
Fuwawa-san, to the food we made...
ピンクやってもらっちゃおうかな、みたいな。
I was thinking of having the pink one done.
牛すじ...
Beef tendon...
あ、たまご。
Oh, an egg.
昆布、牛すじ、たまご...
Kelp, beef tendon, egg...
牛すじと大根あるかな？
Is there beef tendon and daikon radish?
大根あった！
There's daikon!
心におじを飼っている...
Keeping an old man in my heart...
おでーん、おでーん...
Odeeeen, odeeeen...
みっつ！オッケー！
Three! Okay!
ありがとう。
Thank you.
おでんもっといれる？
Want to put in more oden?
おでん、おでん。
Oden, oden.
おでん今日やってもらわない？
Won't you have oden today?
これに今からやってもらうから。
We're going to have it done to this now.
じゃあ、頼めるか、フワモコ？
Then, can I ask you, FUWAMOCO?
オッケー！はい！
Okay! Yes!
力入れますね、ちょっと待って。
I'm going to put some strength into it, wait a bit.
力込めてくれる？
Will you put your heart into it?
おでん様、おでん様...
Lord Oden, Lord Oden...
オッケー、店主の...
Okay, the shopkeeper's...
オッケー！イェーイ！
Okay! Yay!
オッケー、修行が...
Okay, the training...
オッケー！
Okay!
行きますよ！
Here we go!
おいしくなーれ！
Become delicious!
おでん、おでん、きゅーん！
Oden, oden, kyun!
ありがとう！わーい！
Thank you! Yay!
おいしくなーれ！
Become delicious!
やーん！
Yaan!
これ食べていいの？
Can I eat this?
食べよ、食べよ。
Let's eat it.
おいしーい！
Delicious!
いっぱい食べよ。
Eat a lot.
お腹いっぱい。
My stomach is full.
オッケー、でもね...
Okay, but you know...
今日、みんなお仕事がいっぱいあって...
Everyone has a lot of work today...
後ろの時間から来る人も...
And people coming later too...
そうなんだ、ちょっと待って。
I see, wait a second.
頭の中がモクモク...
My head is all fuzzy...
ごちそうさま、おいしーい！
Thank you for the meal, it's delicious!
よかったー、ありがとうございます！
I'm glad, thank you very much!
おいしーい！
Delicious!
天才！
Genius!
My favorite was the soft...
what was it?
Hanpen!
はんぺん、おいしーい！
The hanpen is delicious!
あ、茎！
Oh, kuki!
茎もおいしーい！
The kuki is delicious too!
それもいいですね。
That's good too.
Everything was so yummy.
全部？
Everything?
Hard to pick.
たまごもおいしーい！
The egg is delicious too!
一番好きだったわ。
It was my favorite.
これ、今度は...
Next time, for this...
食べます？
Will you eat?
後で来るんだって、人が。
People are coming later, they said.
オッケー、オッケー。まだいっぱいあります。
Okay, okay. There's still plenty left.
おいしかったな。
That was delicious.
はい。まじで。
Yes. Seriously.
本当に全然スタッフさんに振る舞うつもりで...
I was really intending to serve the staff...
あ、そういうことか。オッケー。
Oh, is that so? Okay.
ちなみに...
By the way...
モコに萌え萌えキュンしてもらったやつは、とてもうまいぞ。
The one Mococo did moe moe kyun to is very tasty.
愛情込めてます。
It's filled with love.
これが愛情こもったおでんなのか。
So this is the oden filled with love.
愛情ですぎて、今から全部愛情係...
There's too much love, so from now on, everyone is the love-department...
やってもらおうかな。
I think I'll have them do it.
大事。
It's important.
愛情係大事だよね。
The love-department is important, isn't it?
おでん、ござるの中のおじさんが目覚めそう。
Oden, the old man inside me is about to wake up.
もう目覚めてるよ。
He's already awake.
目覚めちゃったやーん！
He's woken up!
わー、かわいい！
Wow, so cute!
かわいい。また作ってみるのもやりたい。
Cute. I want to try making it again too.
やりたいです！
I want to do it!
給仕するだけで申し訳ない。
I feel bad for just serving it.
やったー。それがモコが...
Yay. That's what Mococo...
先輩たちが作ってる間にゲームやってて...
Was playing games while the seniors were making it...
何もやってない！
I haven't done anything!
何作りたい？こういう食べ物作りたい、とか。
What do you want to make? Like, some food you want to make.
逆に何食べたいか聞いて。何食べたい？
On the contrary, ask me what I want to eat. What do you want to eat?
作ってもらうなら、練り物も作ってみたいですね。
If you're making it for me, I'd like to try making fish paste products too.
おでん、一から作る...
Making oden from scratch...
一旦おでんか。一緒に...
Oden for now. Together...
工場だね。かまぼこ工場。
A factory. A kamaboko factory.
お味噌作りたいな。
I want to make miso.
えっと、壺にわーって投げて...
Um, throwing it into a jar and...
そう、なんていうか、壺に投げるんですね。
Yes, how should I say, you throw it into a jar.
そういう棚を...
A shelf like that...
そういう元から作るやつを見た。
I've seen things made from the very beginning like that.
番組で。あと梅干しも作ってみたい。
On a show. Also, I want to try making pickled plums.
納豆！納豆も！
Natto! Natto too!
ふわもこに 何作ってもらいたいですか？
What do you want FuwaMoco to make for you?
If we were to cook something, what would you want us to eat?
Like, what would you want us to make for you?
You two?
Yeah!
Probably... what's probably...
Like some candy, like...
What's the word for romantic chocolate?
Yeah, was that...
Chocolate?
本命チョコ！
Honmei choco!
本命チョコに毒されすぎじゃない？
Aren't you a bit too obsessed with "honmei choco"?
本命チョコに毒されてる...
Obsessed with "honmei choco"...
ドーナツ、ドーナツ！
Donuts, donuts!
ドーナツもいいね。
Donuts are also good.
ドーナツ作りたい！作りたい！
I want to make donuts! I want to make them!
ミスド...
Misudo...
ドーナツ作れるの？ かわいい！
You can make donuts? How cute!
揚げ物は怖い。
Deep-frying is scary.
揚げないドーナツだと ちょっと違う。
Baked donuts are a bit different.
でも揚げないとね。
But you have to fry them.
If you don't fry donuts, they're not donuts, right?
What's a donut if it's not fried? That's just cake.
No, the ones that are not... they're no-fry donuts.
Then, no-fry donuts. Hmmm.
揚げてないドーナツは ただのケーキ。
Donuts that aren't fried are just cake.
美味しいけどドーナツじゃないよね。
They're good, but they're not donuts.
時々ラフィアンズが「ドーナツ作ってみました」って Twitterに上げてくれるんです。
Sometimes Ruffians post on Twitter saying, "I tried making donuts."
大惨事だったかな？ 美味しそうだったけど...
Was it a disaster? It looked tasty, though...
なんか事故ってないかな？ 心配になっちゃう。
I wonder if anything went wrong. It makes me worried.
ドーナツは揚げるのは事故らない。あれ大事。
Frying donuts won't fail. That part is important.
揚げないドーナツか。
Unfried donuts, huh.
今度作ってみようかな、揚げドーナツね。
Maybe I'll try making fried donuts next time.
あとハンバーグがいい！
And Hamburg steak!
ハンバーグ！ こねてくれる？
Hamburg steak! Will you knead it for us?
豆腐とチキンの ハンバーグ作るんですね。
We'll make tofu and chicken Hamburg steaks.
チキンではなく多分こねた... スプレッドしてほしい。
Not chicken, but probably kneaded... I want them to spread it.
こねてほしい、手で。
I want them to knead it, by hand.
なんかちょっと引かれてる？
Are they a bit put off?
If you want us to make a hamburger by hand...
And my choco!
本命チョコ！ 本命チョコ！
Honmei choco! Honmei choco!
本命チョコに毒されてる人...
People obsessed with "honmei choco"...
本命チョコに毒されてる人やばい！
People obsessed with "honmei choco" are crazy!
Next time I make... I like making cakes, so I'll make you a German cake.
あ、モココジャーマンケーキ 作るのすごく好きだから。
Oh, Mococo really loves making German cakes.
ジャーマンケーキ！ やった！
German cake! Yay!
I can make... Schwarzwälder Kirschtorte.
A cherry choco cake.
おお、美味しそう！
Ooh, looks tasty!
Or like Baumkuchen.
バウムクーヘン！ くるくるのやつ？
Baumkuchen! The spinning one?
But homemade is just... hmmm... not the circle-circle.
くるくるじゃないでも... そう、レイヤーズ。
It's not circular, but... yeah, layers.
So we have to meet again.
あ、次会う時は...
Oh, next time we meet...
I'm gonna bake for everyone next time.
I'll make even more for everyone here.
教えてほしい、バウムクーヘンの作り方。
I want you to teach us how to make Baumkuchen.
She can cook anything.
おお、何でも！
Ooh, anything!
I'll make you guys American mac and cheese.
おお！マッカンチーズ！
Ooh! Mac and cheese!
Can I tell the story? No, too long.
日本にはあるかな？ マッカンチーズ。
Is there mac and cheese in Japan?
マッカンチーズ... ジャンクフードって感じ。
Mac and cheese... feels like junk food.
マカロニ？ マカロニチーズ？
Macaroni? Macaroni cheese?
謎だけある？
Is it just mystery?
Are you gonna make it from a box?
No, I'll make the actual mac and cheese.
Oh, okay, okay!
So we have main meals, dessert...
Wait!
Did you make this like the...
No, no, no, I made it all!
I like the box!
なんかね、箱から出して、ちょっとジャンクフードなイメージあるので。
Since it's taken out of the box, it has a bit of a junk food feel.
そうですね、なんか箱から出してドンドン！ドンドン！ドンドン！
Yeah, like taking it out of the box and going 'Boom! Boom! Boom!'
出来たてのいろはちゃんの作るのが、特製...
The freshly made one Iroha-chan makes is special...
Honmei choco! Honmei choco! Honmei choco!
Trade! Trade! Trade!
本命が大事なんだ。本命がね。
Honmei (true feelings) is important. Honmei, you see.
Yummy! Delicious! Love it!
AZKi-senpai is sleepy, baby need to go to bed.
Okay, they want us to leave.
Wait, I just wanted a kiss! I just wanted a kiss! Get out of here!
こんな本命欲しがられること、初めてだわ...
I've never been wanted this much for 'honmei' before...
確かにな、この食堂来て、キスを求められるの...
True, coming to this cafeteria and being asked for a kiss...
If only we got a kiss! If only we got a kiss!
If only we got a kiss!
Just a blow kiss?
I really wanted a kiss!
ものすごく、ものすごくキスが欲しいらしい。
It seems they really, really want a kiss.
先輩頑張って！
Senpai, hang in there!
待って、待って！
Wait, wait!
一番違うんです！一番違うんです！
It's the most different! It's the most different!
Thank you so much! Thank you!
Five stars! Five stars!
まつり先輩！
Matsuri-senpai!
See you later everyone! I got a real kiss!
まつりちゃんの本命キスカウンターが...
Matsuri-chan's honmei kiss counter...
上がりました！
...has gone up!
まつり先輩、いい匂い！
Matsuri-senpai, nice smell!
日本語が上手だわ、本当に。
Her Japanese is really good.
ドキドキ！
Doki doki (thump thump)!
しし、じじ、眠い...
Shishi, Gigi, sleepy...
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
皆さん、バイバイ！ありがとうございました！
Everyone, bye bye! Thank you very much!
Chu chu chu!
先輩頑張って！
Senpai, hang in there!
嬉しいよ、本当。
I'm so happy, really.
忘れ物あるかな？スマホとか。
Did she forget anything? Like a smartphone.
Fuwawa, okay?
今日はね、海外メンバーもいっぱいいたからね。行きたいのに行けない...
Today there were a lot of overseas members. They want to go but can't...
ちょっとね、風邪も流行ってるしね、今ね。
Well, a cold is going around too, right now.
海外メンバー来てくれた、めっちゃ。
A lot of overseas members came.
ね、すごいでやんす。
Yeah, it's amazing.
いろはちゃんも、まだ食べれるんですか？クッキー2袋目開けようとして...
Iroha-chan, can you still eat? She's trying to open the second bag of cookies...
クッキータイム！クッキー！
Cookie time! Cookies!
いいですよ、食べてください。卵も食べていいんだもんね。
It's okay, please eat. You can eat eggs too, right.
風真時って常設で売らないの？
Don't you sell 'Kagamatoki' regularly?
常設で売ってほしいよ。常設どこかに販売...
I want it to be sold regularly. Selling it regularly somewhere...
スタジオに置いておくとか？
Like keeping it in the studio?
このクッキー、こないだロボ子先輩にレクチャーしてきたんですけど。
I gave a lecture about these cookies to Roboco-senpai the other day.
今度はまつり先輩の番だなってずっとと思ってて。ちょっとお誘いしようと思って。
I've been thinking it's Matsuri-senpai's turn next. I'm thinking of inviting her.
あー、まだ空いている日とか
Ah, are there any days still open?
あ、もちろんもちろん！
Oh, of course, of course!
100枚焼こう、100枚
Let's bake 100 cookies, 100.
100枚！？
100!?
100枚焼こう100枚
Let's bake 100, 100.
ちなみに前回ですね、ロボ子先輩は
By the way, last time, Roboco-senpai...
めっちゃ頑張って材料とかは全部ロボ子先輩に
...tried really hard, and I told her...
これ買ってきてねーってお使いしてもらってやったんですけど
...'Please buy these,' and had her run errands.
まつり先輩は調理器具がないって
But Matsuri-senpai said she had no tools...
あ、全部買いました！
Oh, I bought them all!
あ、じゃあ行きます！
Oh, then I'll come!
クッキーの型も買ったし
I bought cookie cutters too.
おー、すごい！
Oh, amazing!
そう、ちゃんと全部揃えてある
Yes, I have everything ready.
今揃ってる
It's all ready now.
オーブンもある
I have an oven too.
じゃあ行きます。来てください
Then I'll go. Please come over.
はい、わかりました！
Yes, understood!
やったー！
Yay!
準備ができたということで
Since the preparations are done.
そう、前話したその日に買った全部
Yes, I bought everything the day we talked.
買ったんだ！良かったー
You bought them! That's great.
整いました、色々
Everything is set now.
整ってる。良かったー
It's set. Good.
じゃあ空いてる日教えてくれたら
Then if you let me know when you're free...
はい、送ります！
Yes, I'll send it!
クッキー講座を
...for the cookie workshop.
クッキー講座！
Cookie workshop!
クッキー！クッキー！
Cookies! Cookies!
フワモコもクッキー食べる？
Do FUWAMOCO want to eat cookies too?
しゅごいクッキー！
A-ma-zing cookies!
食べる！チョコチップがいいなー
I'll eat! I want chocolate chip!
ふわぁー、美味しかったー
Huaa, that was delicious.
ねー、めっちゃブリヒミって感じー
Right? It felt so BAU BAU-ish.
あー、ありがとうございます
Ah, thank you.
あ, ありがとうございます
ここにこれ置いておいていいよ
You can leave this here.
一応今日はですね、どうしても来たくて来れなかった人シリーズ
Today, we have the 'Wanted to come but couldn't' series.
リオナさん！
Riona-san!
実はこのクッキー型はですね、リオナさんにもらったやつで
Actually, these cookie cutters were a gift from Riona-san.
クッキー型で焼いた
I baked them with those.
クッキーでした。そうだ紹介ができてなかったと思って
They're cookies. I realized I hadn't introduced them.
そう、リオナからもらったクッキー型の
Yes, using the cutters from Riona...
可愛いクッキー
...made cute cookies.
可愛いな。葉っぱとハート
So cute. Leaf and heart shapes.
他にも色々もらったんだけど、今日はサイズ感の都合でこの2つで
I got others too, but today I used these two due to size.
リオナもね、今日来たいって言ってくれてたんだけど
Riona said she wanted to come today, but...
みんな来たいのに、お仕事とかね
Everyone wants to come, but they have work...
タイミングがねー
The timing is tough.
しかも遅い時間なら行けるんですけどやってますか？とか
She asked, 'Can I go if it's late? Are you open?'
あー、なるほどなるほど
Ah, I see, I see.
クッキー食べる！美味しい！
Eating cookies! Delicious!
クッキーだー
It's a cookie.
クッキーって一番大きいサイズってどこまでなら焼けるの？
What's the biggest size cookie you can bake?
え、マジでデカければデカいほど大変なんですけど
Well, honestly, the bigger it is, the harder it gets.
あ、そうなんだ。夢のクッキー作りたいまつりは
Oh, I see. Matsuri wants to make a dream cookie.
がんばるねー
I'll do my best.
このくらいのクッキーを今日は
I made this size cookie today.
キャラクッキーみたいさ、なんかナイフとかでこうやって型取ったらできる？
Like character cookies, can you trace them with a knife?
お、できます！
Oh, you can!
ただ焼き時間と温度調節が結構シビアかも
But the baking time and temperature are quite strict.
あ、そうなんだー。割れちゃいます？
Oh, really? Do they break?
アイシングクッキーは作ったことある
I've made icing cookies before.
あー、アイシング
Ah, icing.
アイシングだったら結構なんでも大丈夫
With icing, pretty much anything works.
ヒビとか結局アイシングでしちゃえば消えるしね
Cracks will disappear if you cover them with icing.
そうそうそう。え、作りたいなーでもキャラクッキー
Right, right. Man, I want to make character cookies.
まあまつりすなら割れてもいいから作ろう
Well, if it's for Matsurisu, let's make it even if it breaks.
まつりす先輩、ごめんね。割れても大丈夫って言われてる
Matsurisu-senpai, sorry. They say it's fine even if it breaks.
100枚乗っても大丈夫みたいな感じで
Like the 'fine even with 100 people' thing.
えーって言われてますよ
She's saying 'Eh!?'
いいんだよ、いつもそうだから
It's fine, it's always like that.
まつりす、まつりす。はい
Matsurisu, Matsurisu. Yes.
泣いてるよ、まつり先輩
Matsuri-senpai is crying.
可愛いねー
How cute.
そっかー、リオナもね。でもまつり先輩色々揃えたの。フワモコちゃんもそうだし料理を...
I see, Riona too. But Matsuri-senpai got everything ready.
したい！料理会したい！
We want to! We want a cooking stream!
いいですね！デカい鍋とかもね、いつか使うかなーと思って買った
Good! I bought a big pot too, for eventual use.
買ったんだ！すごい
You bought one! Amazing.
おでんもっと食べますか？
Would you like more oden?
え、どうしようかな。でもなんかちょっと遅めに来るメンバーいるんだよね
Hmm, let's see. But some members are coming later.
オッケー！今日は大丈夫なように調節して作ってきてて。この前はマジで怒涛で
Okay! I adjusted it today. Last time was a total rush.
あんなことになるとは思わなかったよね。本当にスタジオにほぼみんな集まってたから
We didn't expect that. Almost everyone was at the studio.
そう、悠久にめっちゃ食べたからね。大根、卵、こんにゃく、ちくわ...
Yeah, we ate so much. Radish, eggs, konnyaku, chikuwa...
はんぺん、餅巾着、牛すじ、ウインナー巻き食べたよ
Hanpen, mochi-kinchaku, beef tendon, and wieners.
いわしの...
The sardine...
そうね、いわしの、いわし、いわしつみれ
Right, sardine... sardine... sardine balls.
私苦手だったの
I used to dislike them.
ロールキャベツ！あ、そうなんだー
Cabbage rolls! Oh, really?
えー、キャベツ苦手なの？
Eh, you dislike cabbage?
キャベツ？火を通した野菜が食べれなくて
Cabbage? I can't eat cooked vegetables.
あ、そうなの！？意外！
Oh, really!? How surprising!
生は好きなんだけど
I like raw ones though.
あー、なるほど。じゃあうちらでやる？一旦さ、おでんロールキャベツ
I see. Then should we do it? Oden cabbage rolls.
確かに。美味しいって言うよね、でも
True. They say they're delicious, though.
やってみますか？丸めて
Shall we try? Rolling them up.
時々のコンソメは食べたんだけど
I ate the occasional consomme one, though.
じゃあちょっと、ロールキャベツを入れてもらっていいですか？
Then, could you add some cabbage rolls?
それをちょっと我々で作ってみようか
Let's try making those ourselves.
ロールキャベツ！ロール、ロール、ロール
Cabbage rolls! Roll, roll, roll.
ロールキャベツは、なんか元々日本のものかなーって
I thought cabbage rolls were originally Japanese.
え、そうなの？
Oh, are they?
クッキングママにあったから、そういうイメージかな
They were in Cooking Mama, so I got that image.
クッキングママが日本のもの
Cooking Mama is Japanese.
これで大丈夫ですか？
Is this okay?
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
あ、ありがとうございます！
Ah, thank you!
大根、卵、こんにゃく、ちくわ...
Radish, eggs, konnyaku, chikuwa...
はんぺん、餅巾着、牛すじ、ウインナー巻き食べたよ
Hanpen, mochi-kinchaku, beef tendon, and wieners.
いわしの...
The sardine...
そうね、いわしの、いわし、いわしつみれ
Right, sardine... sardine... sardine balls.
私苦手だったの。ロールキャベツ！
I used to dislike them. Cabbage rolls!
あ、そうなんだー。えー、キャベツ苦手なの？
Oh, really? Eh, you dislike cabbage?
キャベツ？火を通した野菜が食べれなくて
Cabbage? I can't eat cooked vegetables.
あ、そうなの！？意外！生は好きなんだけど
Oh, really!? Surprising! I like raw ones though.
あー、なるほど。じゃあうちらでやる？
I see. Then should we do it?
一旦さ、おでんロールキャベツ
For now, oden cabbage rolls.
確かに。美味しいって言うよね、でも
True. They say they're delicious, though.
やってみますか？丸めて
Shall we try? Rolling them up.
時々のコンソメは食べたんだけど
I ate the occasional consomme one, though.
じゃあちょっと、ロールキャベツを入れてもらっていいですか？
Then, could you add some cabbage rolls?
それをちょっと我々で作ってみようか
Let's try making those ourselves.
ロールキャベツ！ロール、ロール、ロール
Cabbage rolls! Roll, roll, roll.
ロールキャベツは、なんか元々日本のものかなーって
I thought cabbage rolls were originally Japanese.
え、そうなの？
Oh, are they?
クッキングママにあったから、そういうイメージかな
They were in Cooking Mama, so I got that image.
クッキングママが日本のもの
Cooking Mama is Japanese.
これで大丈夫ですか？
Is this okay?
あ、こっちですね。
Ah, it's this way.
あ、それ？これ？
Ah, that one? This one?
あー！ありがとう！
Ah! Thank you!
われわれですね。
It's for us.
このロールキャベツ...
This roll cabbage...
おでんのロールキャベツって言うのかな？
I wonder if it's called oden roll cabbage?
あ、そう。
Ah, right.
これを...果たして本当にうまいのかという...
As to whether this is actually good...
でも売ってるよね、結構。
But they sell it quite often, right?
これがあったので、せっかくみんなで食べてみますか。
Since we have it, shall we all try it together?
食べたい！箸...
I want to eat! Chopsticks...
あ！ごめんなさい！マジでごめんなさい！めっちゃ叩いちゃって...
Ah! Sorry! I'm so sorry! I hit the mic so hard...
二人で食べるんだったら1、2本...
If two people are eating, then one or two...
あ、私もほしい。
Ah, I want some too.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
落とした時用に。はい、ありがとうございます。
In case I drop it. Yes, thank you very much.
じゃあちょっと...ドリンクは？
Well then... what about drinks?
あ、水がね、自分にあります。
Ah, I have water for myself.
ありました。
You did.
ふーふー！
Fuu fuu!
ここで、ゆっくりお水を飲む...
Drinking water slowly here...
確かに。まつり先輩に、コンソメは...
True. To Matsuri-senpai, consomme is...
ロールキャベツ...
Roll cabbage...
結構いっぱいあるね。
There's quite a lot.
みんな少食だなぁ。
Everyone is a light eater.
まつり先輩マジで強引に食べてくれるから。
Matsuri-senpai will really eat it all forcefully.
ふふふ。
Hehehe.
あ、困ったらまつり先輩呼べばなんとかなるんですね。
Ah, so if we're in trouble, we can just call Matsuri-senpai and it'll be fine.
呼んで。
Call her.
飛んでくるし。
She'll come flying.
そう、飛んできてくれる。
Yes, she'll fly over for us.
何か食べ物あるのかなー？！
I wonder if there's any food?!
おお！来たー！
Oh! She's here!
何か食べ物あるのかなー？！
I wonder if there's any food?!
ベーちゃん！
Bae-chan!
おでん、おでん。唐揚げもある。
Oden, oden. There's karaage too.
最高！もう...
Awesome! I'm...
お腹空いた。
I'm hungry.
いっぱい食べますか？
Will you eat a lot?
うん！じゃあ、自己紹介お願いします。
Yeah! Well then, self-introduction please.
我はカオス...マイクどこだ？
I am Chaos... where's the mic?
その、上。
It's up there.
我はカオス、理の果て、ジ・エンド、氷のリフ、最上級、汝の共、滅びへの博士、ベールズです！
I am Chaos, the end of reason, The End, ice rift, supreme, your companion, the doctor of destruction, Baelz!
おおー！
Ooooh!
お邪魔しまーす。
Excuse me for interrupting.
唐揚げいります？
Do you want some karaage?
食べる。
I'll eat.
何個いる？
How many do you want?
1個。1個でいい。
One. One is fine.
じゃあとりあえず。まあおでんもあるわ。
Well, for now. There's oden too.
あ、おでんも食べたい。ありがとう。
Ah, I want to eat oden too. Thank you.
ドリンクは？
Drinks?
おでおでんキュン！もしもし？
Ode-oden kyun! Hello hello?
おでおでんキュン、レギュラーメニュー化すっかな。
I should make "Ode-oden kyun" a regular menu item.
マジか。いいのか。
Really. Is it okay?
そういう店です。で、今回こちらにですね...
That's the kind of shop this is. So, here we have...
おでんのお品書きがありますので。
We have an oden menu.
食べたいやつをフワモコちゃんに言うと、頑張って取ってくれます。
If you tell Fuwamoco what you want to eat, they'll do their best to get it for you.
おおー、おいで！
Oh, come here!
今日お給仕係フワモコちゃん。
Today the servers are Fuwamoco-chan.
はいはいはい！はーい！
Yes yes yes! Here!
えー、えー...僕は大根。
Uh, uh... I'll have daikon.
大根、オッケー。卵。
Daikon, okay. Egg.
卵。オッケー。あとは...
Egg. Okay. And...
ちくわ。オッケー。
Chikuwa. Okay.
ちくわ、ダブルちくわ、おね。
Chikuwa, double chikuwa, please.
ちくわ、トリプル、トリプルちくわ。
Chikuwa, triple, triple chikuwa.
ちくわ好きだね、そんなに食べれる？
You like chikuwa, don't you? Can you eat that many?
美味しいんだな。
They're delicious.
ちくわ大好き！ちくわ大好きなんだな。
I love chikuwa! I really love chikuwa.
卵も。卵、ちくわ。
Egg too. Egg, chikuwa.
はい、お願いします。
Yes, please.
オッケー！
Okay!
あと卵も。それとはんぺん。
Also an egg. And hampen.
卵。あったあった。これ。
Egg. Found it, found it. This one.
お姉ちゃん聞いてなかったでしょ。
Onee-chan, you weren't listening, were you?
え？卵。卵、卵。え、ちょっと待って。
Eh? Egg. Egg, egg. Wait a minute.
どこ？え、ちょっと待って。
Where? Eh, wait a minute.
卵は...あ、卵は最高すぎる。
Egg is... ah, egg is just the best.
よかった。ありがと。
Good. Thanks.
いらっしゃいませ！
Welcome!
いつもご飯の時来てる気がする。
I feel like I'm always here when there's food.
ありがたいことに。いやいやいや。
Thankfully. No no no.
大体来てくれる。ぜひぜひ、ご飯一緒に食べたい。
You usually come. Definitely, I want to eat together.
久しぶりじゃない？クリスマスの時に...
Hasn't it been a while? Since Christmas...
あ、そう。めっちゃ来たんだけどさ、もう、やば。
Ah, right. I've been here so much, but man, it's crazy.
スケジュールやばって、お互いにね。
Our schedules were crazy, for both of us.
そうなんですよ。で、今回来れて本当に良かった。ちょうどね。
That's right. So, it's really good you could come this time. Just in time.
良かったー！楽しい。
I'm so glad! This is fun.
今日はいっぱい食べてってくれ。
Please eat a lot today.
食べる。
I will.
ベーちゃんのお茶ね。
This is Bae-chan's tea.
かわいい！ちょっと！
Cute! Wait!
やばい。これ。
Oh no. This.
違う店始まってるから。
A different shop has started.
違う店始まっておる。
A different shop is starting.
はい。ちょっと待って、これ、やばい。
Yes. Wait a minute, this is dangerous.
絶対見せられない中入ってるから。
There's something inside that I absolutely can't show.
いや、これ急速で飲むから後で見せます。
No, I'll drink this quickly and show you later.
じゃあちょっと、ここカメラエリアなんで気をつけて。
Well then, watch out, this is the camera area.
はい、これがベーの卵、ちくわ、こんにゃく、大根が入ってます。
Yes, this is Bae's egg, chikuwa, konjac, and daikon.
ありがとう、ありがとうございます。
Thank you, thank you very much.
はい。おでおでんキュンは入りますか？
Yes. Would you like some "Ode-oden kyun"?
あ、おでん美味しくする...
Ah, to make the oden delicious...
おでおでんキュン！やべっ、忘れてた。
Ode-oden kyun! Oops, I forgot.
オッケー！オッケー！
Okay! Okay!
はい、いきます！せーの！
Yes, here I go! One, two!
おでんくなれ、おでおでんキュン！
Become oden-y, Ode-oden kyun!
かわいい！はんぺんはんぺんはんぺん。
Cute! Hampen hampen hampen.
はんぺん？あれ？
Hampen? Eh?
むー。こっちはんぺん。
Moo. Here's hampen.
ハートじゃなくてはんぺん。
Not a heart, but hampen.
はんぺんね！かわいい。
Hampen, right! Cute.
ありがとうございます。食べて。
Thank you. Please eat.
いっぱい食べよう。
Let's eat a lot.
いや、これちょっと、まつり先輩の絵を、ちょっと見せないといけない。
Wait, I have to show Matsuri-senpai's drawing for a bit.
あ、結構な量のお茶いれちゃった。
Ah, I poured quite a bit of tea.
ゆっくりで。まかせろ。
Take your time. Leave it to me.
ちょっと、これ見せますね。
I'll show this now.
無理させちゃった。
I made her work too hard.
可愛いー！
Cute!
上手！
Good job!
わかりやすいように書いたよ。
I wrote it so it's easy to understand.
大事なお茶をごめん。
Sorry about the precious tea.
なんで？あ、お茶いっぱい入れちゃった。
Why? Ah, I poured too much tea.
いただきます！
Let's eat!
そうですよね、日本のご飯大好き。
Right, I love Japanese food.
いつも美味しいって食べてくれる。作ったもの。
She always says it's delicious when she eats what I make.
なんでも食べますよ。
I eat anything.
好き嫌いとかないですか？
Are there things you don't like?
ない。
None.
すごい！
Amazing!
アレルギー以外はない。
None except allergies.
確かにいつも何出してもだいたい何でも食べてくれますね。
True, she usually eats almost anything I serve.
好き嫌いなし！
No likes or dislikes!
おでんロールキャベツありだ。全然。
Oden cabbage roll is totally okay.
卵の黄身めちゃくちゃでかいんだけど。
The egg yolk is huge!
当たり！
Jackpot!
おおきい！
Big!
なんでこんなにおっきいの？
Why is it so big?
ハッピーハッピーがね、ゆで卵作る時は、いつもなんかグリーンになっちゃうんですけど、すげぇ。
When I make boiled eggs, the yolk usually turns green... this is amazing.
ちょっとこれ見せていい？
Can I show this?
めちゃ大きい。
It's very big.
みんなに見せたいぐらいデカい。
It's big enough that I want to show everyone.
おっきな黄身！
Big yolk!
えー！デカ！
Eh! Huge!
デカすぎる！
Too big!
当たりだ！
Jackpot!
おにぎり食べてください。
Please eat the rice ball.
ロールキャベツおでんあり、ありです、これ。
Cabbage roll oden is a yes, definitely.
あのお出汁でさ、なんか調和されてる。
It's harmonized by that dashi.
ロールキャベツって普通おでんに入らないですか？
Don't cabbage rolls usually go in oden?
あんまり入らない。
Not really.
メジャーではない、確かに。
Not major, true.
お店とかだとちょいちょいあるけど、やっぱ家だと面倒くさいし。
You see it in shops sometimes, but at home it's a hassle.
頑張りましたから、あずいろは。
We worked hard on it, Azuiro.
もう、最高すぎる。
It's just too good.
めっちゃお仕事してたの？うん、えらい。
Were you working hard? Yeah, good girl.
お腹空いたね。みんなフェスの準備とか忙しいからね、みんな。
You're hungry, right? Everyone's busy with Fes prep.
大変な中、今日はありがとうございます。
Thank you for coming despite being so busy today.
何時頃やってたんですか？
What time were you doing it?
8時から開けて... ただやっぱ、まつりちゃんとかにスケジュール聞いた感じも...
We opened at 8... but true, asking Matsuri-chan and others about their schedules...
みんな大体これくらいの時間にお仕事が終わることが多かったりとか。
Many people finish work around this time.
お腹空かせて来る人いとおしいって感じで。
It's lovely how people come here hungry.
まつ先輩いつもお腹空かせて来る。
Matsu-senpai always comes here hungry.
今日も何も食べずに来たの？あー、ちゃんと食べないと。
You came today without eating anything either? Ah, you should eat properly.
おにぎり持ち帰ってもいい？一個。
Can I take a rice ball home? One.
いいよ。
Sure.
梅干しも自家製だから。
The pickled plums are homemade too.
梅干し食べたことない。
I've never eaten a pickled plum.
え？なんで？
Eh? Why?
おにぎり鮭とツナマヨしか食べたことない。
I've only ever eaten salmon and tuna mayo rice balls.
え？お弁当に乗ってたりするじゃん。
Eh? They're often in lunch boxes.
食べたことない。
Never.
噂で酸っぱいと聞いてるから。
I've heard rumors that they're sour.
酸っぱい苦手じゃない？
Aren't you bad with sour things?
食べたことないから分かんない。
I don't know because I've never tried.
酸っぱいものは好き？
Do you like sour things?
酸っぱいもの食べたことない。
I've never eaten sour things.
レモンは？
What about lemons?
レモンはアレルギーで食べれないし。
I can't eat lemons because of an allergy.
クエン酸... 柑橘類が... 柚子とか。
Citric acid... citrus fruits like yuzu.
えっ、スパキャンとかも？
Wait, even things like candy?
あ、あれ果汁入ってないから大丈夫。
Oh, those don't have fruit juice, so it's fine.
いいか。
I see.
みかんもアレルギーだ。
I'm allergic to mikan too.
柑橘全般...?
All citrus fruits...?
あ、でもくん様はなめれるよ。
Oh, but I can lick Kun-sama.
くんさんな。
Don't eat him.
大丈夫、大丈夫。
It's okay, it's okay.
えー、どうなるんだろうね。
Wow, I wonder how it'll be.
えー、独特な味をするとわするけど。
Well, I think it has a unique taste, but...
楽しみ。
I'm looking forward to it.
おかかとか昆布もない？食べたこと。
What about bonito flakes or kelp? Have you eaten them?
あ、そうなんですか。
Oh, is that so?
それがアレルギーとかじゃない？
Is that because of an allergy or something?
じゃない。
No, it's not.
えー。
What?
偏食？
Are you a picky eater?
えー、すごい。そうなんだ。
Wow, that's surprising. I see.
なかなか避けて通れない。
It's pretty hard to avoid those here.
どうかな。
I wonder.
避けて通れなくても無理じゃないですか。
Even if I can't avoid them, isn't it impossible?
鮭とツナマヨだけで生きてきた。
I've lived on nothing but salmon and tuna mayo.
鮭とツナマヨでおにぎり、絶対どこかで出会う。
Salmon and tuna mayo rice balls,
you'll definitely encounter them somewhere.
絶対どこかで出会う。
You'll definitely encounter them somewhere.
どこかで出会う。
Encounter them somewhere.
ね。
Right.
えー。
Wow.
そうなんだ。
Is that so.
チョコミントも食べたことないよ。
I've never eaten mint chocolate either.
あ、チョコミントは食べなくていい。
Oh, you don't have to eat mint chocolate.
チョコミント党に怒られる、べーちゃん。
The mint chocolate lovers will get mad, Bae-chan.
やばいやばい。
Oh no, oh no.
チョコミント党。
Mint chocolate lovers.
食べなくていい。チョコミント党に怒られるよ。
You don't have to eat it. The mint chocolate lovers will get mad.
チョコミント党に。
By the mint chocolate lovers.
何？チョコミント党いるぞ、多分。
What? There are probably mint chocolate lovers here.
えー。
What?
チョコミント、チョコミント。
Mint chocolate, mint chocolate.
いや、チョコミントよりミントの方が好き。
Actually, I like mint more than mint chocolate.
チョコなくてもいい派ね。
So you're in the "no chocolate needed" camp.
そう、それぞれ。
Yes, to each their own.
邪魔。
It's in the way.
チョコミント混ぜる必要ないよね。
There's no need to mix chocolate and mint, right?
うん、ミントだけで美味しい。
Yeah, mint alone is delicious.
え、べーべーはチョコだけでいい人？
Wait, Bae-Bae, are you a "chocolate only" person?
ミントだけでいい？
Or "mint only"?
いや。
No.
なんか... あの...
Like... um...
あれ。
That.
わざわざトゥースペーストにチョコを一緒に食わないじゃん。
You don't go out of your way to eat chocolate
with toothpaste, do you?
そうだよね、それも分かる。
Right, I get that too.
トゥースペーストだけ食べたいよね。
You want to eat just the toothpaste, right?
いや、それはないね。
No, that's not it.
あ、そっちじゃない？
Oh, not that way?
やばいやばい、コメント欄のチョコミントが...
Oh no, oh no, the mint chocolate lovers in the chat...
待って待って、怒ってる。
Wait, wait, they're angry.
顔真っ赤。
Their faces are red with anger.
顔真っ赤で笑った。
LMAO at the red faces.
まあまあ、ちょっとね、チョコミントはね。
Now, now, about mint chocolate...
あの、なんていうかね、僕はね、ちょっと神の舌持ってるから。
How should I put it... I have a refined palate.
神の舌。
A divine palate.
凡人の舌はちょっと理解できない、敵には。
I can't understand the commoners' taste... I've made enemies.
敵に回した。
You've turned them into enemies.
色可愛いけどね。
The color is cute, though.
あー。
Ah.
今日可愛いね。
You're cute today.
あ、衣装も可愛いよ、べーちゃん。
Your outfit is cute too, Bae-chan.
やばい、今炎上中。
Oh no, I'm currently getting flamed.
そう、今炎上してる、べーちゃんが。
Yes, Bae-chan is being flamed right now.
チョコミント美味しくないって言って炎上した。
She's getting flamed for saying mint chocolate isn't tasty.
あ、座ってもいい？
Oh, can I sit down?
いいよ。
Sure.
座って。
Sit down.
皆さんのお隣に。
Right next to everyone.
いいかな。
Is it okay?
大丈夫ですよ。
It's fine.
唐揚げ食べる？
Do you want some fried chicken?
え、食べる！めちゃくちゃ美味い。
Oh, I'll eat it! It's super delicious.
おでんも。
Oden too.
おでん。
Oden.
来てくださったのは？
And the person joining us is...?
じゃ、自己紹介をお願いします。
Well, please introduce yourself.
あ、自己紹介、忘れてた。
Oh, introduction, I forgot.
あ、マイクは？
Oh, where's the mic?
頭の上。
Above your head.
え、あ、ここ？
Eh, oh, here?
あ、あ、あ、ミーシャ...
Ah, ah, ah, Mic check...
Hi, Start! ホロライブ English Promise のハコス・ベールズです！
Hi, Start! I'm Hakos Baelz from Hololive English Promise!
イエーイ！
Yay!
おでんいっぱい食べる、と唐揚げ1個。
Eat lots of oden, and one piece of fried chicken.
温かい唐揚げきた！
Warm fried chicken is here!
あ、温かい唐揚げ食べてね。
Oh, please eat the warm fried chicken.
最高！
The best!
おでん。
Oden.
おでん食べたことある？
Have you ever eaten oden?
えっと、ない。
Um, no.
覚えてない。
I don't remember.
ないかも。
Maybe not.
ない。
None.
初めてのおでんきた！
Her first oden is here!
おでん、おでん。
Oden, oden.
じゃあ、何食べるかな。
Well, what should I eat?
あ、メニューがあるんだ。
Oh, there's a menu.
たまごあるかな、まだ。
I wonder if there are still eggs.
たまご美味しいよね。
Eggs are delicious, right?
ガッチャ。おっ。
Gotcha. Oh.
うわ、お、お。おでんがいっぱい。
Wow, look. Lots of oden.
まるまる。まるまるだ。
Round ones. They're round.
いいよ、この方が可愛いからね。
It's okay, they're cuter this way.
ネズミっていう生き物は、丸い方が可愛い。
As creatures called mice, they're cuter when they're round.
じゃあ...
Well...
まるまる、まる。
Round, round, round.
やばい、マシュマロだ。
Oh no, it's a marshmallow.
大根美味しい。
Daikon is delicious.
美味しい。
Delicious.
大根食べたい。
I want to eat daikon.
大根、こんにゃく、ちくわ、はんぺん... オッケー。
Daikon, konjac, chikuwa, hanpen... okay.
いっぱいあるよ。
There's plenty.
あ、オッケーオッケー。
Ah, okay okay.
おすすめ。
Recommended.
よし、じゃあ大根、こんにゃく、ちくわ。
Alright, so daikon, konjac, and chikuwa.
大根、こんにゃく、ちくわ。
Daikon, konjac, chikuwa.
こんにゃく、ちくわ。
Konjac, chikuwa.
あとさつま揚げを入れてあげてください。
And please put in some satsuma-age too.
オッケー。
Okay.
ちくわ知らない？
You don't know chikuwa?
知らない。
I don't know.
Fish cake.
大根も。
Daikon too.
知らない。
Don't know.
大根も知らないの？
You don't know daikon either?
いや、ENとIDが来てくれるとこれがあるから面白い。
It's interesting because this happens
when EN and ID members come.
面白いよね。
It is interesting, isn't it?
そう。
Yeah.
おっ。
Oh.
あ、あのネズミの代わりで。
Ah, instead of that mouse.
ありますよ、ありますよ。
We have it, we have it.
もちろんあります。
Of course we have it.
ドリンクはどうします？
What would you like for a drink?
お茶？
Tea?
紅茶入れちゃって。
I'll put some black tea in.
あ、それは、えっと紅茶？
Oh, that's, um, black tea?
あ、ティー。
Ah, tea.
大根、たまご、さつま揚げとかはんぺんとか多分ある。
We probably have daikon, egg, satsuma-age, and hanpen.
美味しそう。
Looks delicious.
あ、いよいよですね。
Oh, it's finally time.
もしもし、ちくわ、ちくわ、ちくわ
Hello, chikuwa, chikuwa, chikuwa.
ちくわ！
Chikuwa!
ちくわまだあるよ。
There's still some chikuwa left.
やったーい！
Yay!
卵、卵もないかも。
Egg, there might not be any eggs left.
卵、売り切れ。
Eggs are sold out.
卵売り切れ！売り切れ！売り切れ！
Eggs are sold out! Sold out! Sold out!
あ、最後取っちゃった。あ、ごめん。
Oh, I took the last one. Sorry.
はんぺん。
Hanpen.
あ、ごめんね。
Ah, sorry.
デカ大当たり卵。
The big lucky egg.
あ、デカ大当たり、はんぺん。はい。
Ah, the big lucky hanpen. Here.
あ、キャベツロール！
Oh, cabbage roll!
あ、いいよ、食べて。
Oh, go ahead, eat it.
うん、おいしい！
Yeah, it's delicious!
すごいよね。
It's amazing.
じゃあ、ぜいたくちゃんの。
Then, for the extravagant one.
AZKi先輩の。
AZKi-senpai's.
じゃあね、おまかせ... 私のおすすめで詰めています。
Well, I'm filling it with my recommendations.
はんぺんとこんにゃく、大根。
Hanpen, konjac, and daikon.
あとは、練り物系が...
And then some fish paste products...
あと大根とかも色々いっぱい入ってます。
...and also daikon and lots of other things.
やったー！
Yay!
温かいから、こちら、大事に持って。
It's hot, so hold this carefully.
あ、大事に持ちます。
Ah, I'll hold it carefully.
おでん、おでん！
Oden, oden!
あ、そうだ。大事だった。
Oh, that's right. It was important.
待って、待って！
Wait, wait!
行きますよ。
Here we go.
おでん、おでん、おでん、きゅーい！
Oden, oden, oden, kyu-i!
わお！
Wow!
わんわん！
Bau bau!
ありがとう。
Thank you.
おでん、サンキュー。
Oden, thank you.
AZKi先輩。
AZKi-senpai.
はんぺんの形だ。
It's the shape of hanpen.
はんぺん、すごいふわふわでおいしい。
The hanpen is so fluffy and delicious.
よかった。
I'm glad.
今日もね、笑顔になるよ。
It'll make you smile today too.
はんぺんだそうで。
It seems it's hanpen.
おいしい。はんぺんうまいよね。
Delicious. Hanpen is good, isn't it?
ママ、大丈夫ですか？
Mama, are you okay?
あ、大丈夫だ、うん。
Ah, I'm okay, yeah.
おいしい、おいしい。
Delicious, delicious.
お、おいしいから。いっそう、進むわ。
Oh, because it's delicious, I'm making progress.
昆布。
Kelp.
もっとね、昆布食べる。
I'll eat more kelp.
昆布食べていいよ。
You can eat the kelp.
あ、おいしかったから。普通は食べないけど、健康にいいよね。
Ah, because it was delicious. I usually don't eat it, but it's good for health.
うん、食べて食べて。
Yeah, eat it, eat it.
イエス、ベイビー！
Yes, baby!
あ、来た！
Ah, it's here!
ベイビー、第2回お代わりだよ。
Baby, it's the second helping.
おい！
Hey!
卵もお代わり、きゅーいしたから。
I also got seconds on eggs, kyu-i!
ないよ。
There's none left.
お代わり。お代わり。
Seconds. Seconds.
お代わりもないかも。
There might not be any seconds left.
普通に晩ご飯食べに来た。
I just came here to eat dinner.
びっくりするほどなくなってる。
It's gone surprisingly fast.
すごい。
Amazing.
やばい、幸せすぎる。
Oh my, this is too much happiness.
あの、無限の鍋だったのに。
Even though it was an infinite pot.
あれ、溢れちゃった。ごめんごめん。
Oh, I spilled some. Sorry, sorry.
大丈夫。
It's okay.
いいよ、昆布食べな。
It's okay, eat the kelp.
オッケー、食べて。
Okay, eat it.
うわ、おいしかった。
Wow, it was delicious.
実は昆布あんまり好きじゃないけど、おいしかった。
Actually, I don't like kelp much, but this was delicious.
ね、よかった。
See, I'm glad.
こんにゃくも食べたいけど、全然食べてないよね、もこちゃん。
I want to eat konjac too, but you haven't eaten any at all, Mococo-chan.
あ、何入ってましたっけ？
Ah, what was in it again?
キャベツロール初めて。
First time having a cabbage roll.
キャベツロール初めて？
First time having a cabbage roll?
ええとね、キャベツの中、お肉。
Well, there's meat inside the cabbage.
合いびき、ハンバーグみたいな。
Ground meat, like a hamburger.
あ、見せて、これ。
Ah, show me this.
かわいい！
Cute!
えー、かわいい！
Wow, so cute!
一緒にミックスで出たの。
It came out in a mix together.
なるほど！えー、ありがとう。
I see! Wow, thank you.
かわいい！
Cute!
ちょっとね、ロールキャベツ。ロールキャベツ書いたの。
A little bit, roll cabbage. I wrote 'roll cabbage'.
えー、初めて。
Wow, the first time.
え、初めてなんだ。
Oh, it's your first time.
もったいなくて食べられない、どうしよう。
It's too precious to eat, what should I do?
考えよう。ロールキャベツは作るの大変なんだ。
Let's think. Making cabbage rolls is hard work.
どう？
How is it?
オー、キャン。
Oh, can.
中にお肉がいっぱい。
There's lots of meat inside.
お、踊ってる、踊ってる。
Oh, it's dancing, it's dancing.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
めっちゃお肉うまい。やばい、写真撮ろう。
The meat is so good. Oh man, I'm gonna take a picture.
あ、ロールキャベツ初、べーちゃん食べてくれた。
Ah, first cabbage roll, Bae-chan ate it.
あ、嬉しい。
Ah, I'm happy.
これは、でも、あれ、これは、あっちにあったやつ。
But this, wait, this is the one that was over there.
あ、そう、あっち。
Ah, yes, over there.
それ、コンソメ味。
That one is consomme flavored.
コンソメ味！
Consomme flavor!
うまい。実はおおでんの中にも入ってます。
Good. Actually, it's also in the oden.
そう、おでんの出汁のパターンと...
Right, the oden broth version and...
...その、コンソメの出汁のパターン。
...that consomme broth version.
ロールキャベツ、色々ある。
There are various cabbage rolls.
トマトもあるよ。
There's tomato too.
そうそう、トマト。わざわざよく作るのはトマト味っていうので...
Right, tomato. I usually make tomato flavor, and it was the same...
一致してたけど、今日はコンソメと、あの、おでん出汁に、新たに。新たに。
...but today we have consomme and, well, oden broth, new ones. New ones.
うまーい。
Delicious.
私、ロールキャベツよく、なんか食べたことないかも。
I, somehow, might not have eaten cabbage rolls much.
お、食べ、食べ、食べる？
Oh, eat, eat, eat?
食べる！
I'll eat!
1個ある、ここ。あ、半分こする？
There's one here. Oh, want to split it?
普通の食べるか、おでんの。
Eat the regular one or the oden one.
おでん、食べる！
Oden, I'll eat!
あ、こっちの。
Ah, this one.
大丈夫かい？
Are you okay?
普通のコンソメ？
Regular consomme?
知らないんだよ、今おでんのだから。
I don't know, it's the oden one right now.
オッケー、オッケー。
Okay, okay.
大丈夫か？おでんにする？
Are you okay? You want oden?
おでんの出汁か。あの、コンソメもあります、コンソメ。
Oden broth, then. There's also consomme, consomme.
あ、お、今のおでんにします。
Ah, I'll go with the oden one for now.
今のおでんキャベツ。
This oden cabbage.
僕の前でボール3つ、あれ、あるんぜ。
I have three bowls in front of me, you know.
取って取って。
Take it, take it.
豪華すぎる。
It's too luxurious.
本当だ。
It really is.
バイキング。
Viking (Buffet).
ビュッフェ。
Buffet.
ビュッフェだ。もう僕の前でボール3つがありますから。食べ放題、食べ放題。
It's a buffet. Since there are three bowls in front of me. All-you-can-eat, all-you-can-eat.
おでん食べ放題！
All-you-can-eat oden!
うわ、最高すぎる。
Wow, it's too great.
どうですか？
How is it?
食べ、食べ。
Eat, eat.
すごいジューシー。
It's so juicy.
作った甲斐がありました。
It was worth making.
手羽先、手羽先... 手羽先の分が報われた気がする。
Chicken wings, chicken wings... I feel like the chicken wings were rewarded.
報われたよ。
They were rewarded.
We only roll cabbage.
お、モア・ロールキャベツ。
Oh, more roll cabbage.
ロールキャベツ。
Roll cabbage.
It happens, it happens.
いや、おいしい。
No, it's delicious.
出た、出た！どう、おでん？
It's out, it's out! How's the oden?
めっちゃおいしい。
It's really delicious.
やーい。
Yay.
好きな具材をなんかね、どれがおいしかったとかね。教えてください。
Let me know which ingredients you liked or which were delicious. Please tell me.
全部おいしい。
Everything is delicious.
なんだけど、これ...
Anyway, this...
どれ？どれだ？
Which one? Which one is it?
はんぺん！
Hanpen!
おー！はんぺん！おいしい！
Oh! Hanpen! It's delicious!
はんぺんが刺さってた。
A Hanpen was skewered.
AZKiにははんぺんが刺さってた。大人気だ。
Hanpen was skewered for AZKi. It's really popular.
はんぺんね、大人気だ。
Hanpen is really popular, isn't it?
はんぺんうまいわ。
Hanpen is so good.
ソフトなのがいいのか、テクスチャがいい。
Is it the softness? The texture is great.
食感なのかな？味？
Is it the texture? Or the taste?
そうね、よくわからないかも。
Yeah, I'm not really sure.
はんぺんは...
Hanpen is...
なんか、はんぺんの食感は、しょっぱいマシュマロみたい。
Somehow, Hanpen's texture is like a salty marshmallow.
あー！例えがめちゃくちゃ的確かも。
Ah! That's a spot-on analogy.
的確だわ。
It really is spot on.
食べよう。
Let's eat.
あーんしてる！あーんしてる！
She's feeding her! She's feeding her!
おじさんレーダー早いです。
The Old Man Radar is picking that up fast.
いや、わかる。良からぬことじゃないから。こんにゃくおいしい。
I get it. It's not a bad thing. This konnyaku is good.
こんにゃくおいしい。
Konnyaku is delicious.
わかる。凝視しそうになったのを抑えたんですから。
I know. I suppressed my urge to stare.
抑えたんですから。
I suppressed it.
もう一回見れるかな？
Can I see that again?
おじさんレーダー、ずっと今日戦ってるんだよ、風真は。
Kazama's Old Man Radar has been in a constant battle today.
おじさんレーダー、いや、不安もコアはね。
Old Man Radar... no, even in her core...
おじさんレーダーをくすぐるものがいっぱいある。
There are so many things that tickle the Old Man Radar.
しっぽと耳をいつモフっていいのか。
Like when it's okay to fluff the tail and ears.
ずっと頑張ってる。モフれない...
I'm doing my best. I can't fluff them...
Don't touchって言われちゃうから。
Because I'll be told 'Don't touch'.
まだ嫌われたくない。
I don't want to be hated yet.
嫌われたくない。
I don't want to be hated.
唐揚げ。
Fried chicken.
これ取り分けるよ。
I'll serve this.
これ用のお皿。
Here's a plate for it.
ふわふわ... 何個食べる？
Fluffy... How many do you want?
本当はしっぽモフりたい。
Actually, I want to fluff the tail.
モフモフしたい。今日は我慢。
I want to fluff it, but I'll hold back today.
今日は他人のチャンネルだし自重してるんだ。
Today is on someone else's channel, so I'm behaving.
それ取り分け用の箸だから。
Those are the serving chopsticks.
危ない、危ない！危ない！危ない！
Careful, careful! Careful, careful!
逃げないで！
Don't run away!
うわー、最高の景色だ。
Wow, what a great view.
美味い飯を食べながら、可愛い子を眺める。
Eating good food while looking at cute girls.
ここ一番おじさんが出てた。
That's the most your inner old man has come out.
最高の景色だ。
It's the best view.
すごい、おじさんしかいない。
Wow, it's just full of old men here.
おっさいま、すみません。
Sorry for being so 'old man'-like just now.
パワー増すな、嬉しいな。
The power is increasing, I'm happy.
美味い、お腹いっぱい。
Delicious, I'm full.
ねぇねぇ、風真、今日はお土産のクッキーはないの？
Hey, Kazama, are there no souvenir cookies today?
今日はみんなでつまんでもらおうと思って。
I thought everyone could just snack on them today.
そこに袋があるでしょ。
There's a bag over there.
そこに袋がある。
ちなみに控室にいい感じのプラバックがあって。
By the way, there's a nice plastic bag in the waiting room.
お弁当箱みたいな。
Like a lunch box.
唐揚げをよかったら。
Help yourselves to some fried chicken.
本当ですか！？
Really!?
おー！
Ohhh!
お疲れ様です！お疲れ様です！
Good work! Good work!
日々お仕事。日々お仕事。
Working hard every day. Working hard every day.
ヤッホー！
Yahoo!
じゃあ、そこに座って自己紹介をお願いします。
Okay, please sit there and introduce yourselves.
せーの！
One, two...
ばうばう！
Bau Bau!
お久しぶりです！きらきら、きらばうばうです！
Long time no see! We are the sparkling Kira-Bau Bau!
こんばんは！
Good evening!
お久しぶりです！お久しぶりです！
Long time no see! Long time no see!
すごい美味しそうな匂い！
It smells so delicious!
充満してる！
The room is filled with it!
お腹空いてきました。
I'm getting hungry.
今日はいっぱいおでんあります！
We have lots of oden today!
あ、卵が品切れになりました。
Oh, eggs are already sold out.
すみません、食べちゃった。
Sorry, I ate them.
すみません。食べちゃった。
Sorry. I ate them.
ここに、おでんの具の...
Here are the oden ingredients...
ロールキャベツとかまだあります。
We still have things like roll cabbage.
食べたい具を言ってもらうと。
Just let us know what you want to eat.
モコちゃんがおでんの名前と見た目が一致してないんだけど。
Mococo hasn't matched the names and looks of the oden yet.
頑張って付いてきている。
But she's trying her best to follow along.
もち巾着！もち巾着！
Mochi Kinchaku! Mochi Kinchaku!
売り切れたかも...
It might be sold out...
大人気すぎた。
It was way too popular.
じゃあ、こんにゃくありますか？
Then, do you have any konnyaku?
こんにゃくあります！
We have konnyaku!
こんにゃくとロールキャベツ。
Konnyaku and roll cabbage.
ロールキャベツ、はい！
Roll cabbage, coming up!
乾杯！乾杯！
Cheers! Cheers!
はんぺん、おすすめだよ。
I highly recommend the Hanpen.
いただきます。
Let's eat.
はんぺんを...
The hanpen...
はんぺん、みんなに人気で、すごい美味しい。
Hanpen is popular with everyone, it's really delicious.
美味しい！
It's delicious!
食べたことない？
Have you never eaten it?
はい。自ら選ばないかも。
Yes. I might not choose it myself.
ええー！？うそだー！
What!? No way!
だってはんぺん食べたことあった？
But had you ever eaten hanpen before?
あと昆布とかさつま揚げ...
And kelp, fried fishcakes...
おおー！完食！完食絶対。美味しい！
Oh! We'll finish it! Definitely finish it. Delicious!
昆布？昆布美味しいよ。
Kelp? Kelp is delicious.
昆布も食べたことないかも、おでんの。
I might not have eaten kelp in oden either.
ええー！？普通、普通ですよ。
What!? It's normal, it's normal.
じゃあ、一回、じゃあ、ちょっとサービスします。
Then, for now, I'll give you a little service.
なんか、うち食堂なんですけど、メイド喫茶みたいな特別なサービスが...
Well, this is a cafeteria, but we have special maid cafe-like service...
じゃあ、こちらでお願いします。
Please, right here.
お金取られないですか？取られないです。
You won't charge me, right? No, we won't.
じゃあ、ちょっとやっていただきましょうか、お二人に。
Then, let's have the two of you do it.
お正月、お正月のご奉公はよく効くと言われてるので。
They say service during New Year's is very effective.
あ、バウ！いい響きですね。
Ah, Bau! That has a nice ring to it.
いきますよ！
Here we go!
おいしくなーれ！萌え萌え、バウバウ、キュン！
Become delicious! Moe moe, Bau bau, Kyun!
わあー！おいしくなったー！よかったー！
Wow! It became delicious! Thank goodness!
おいしくなった気がする。よかったです。
I feel like it's more delicious. I'm glad.
あとは向こうに、唐揚げとかクッキーとか、おにぎりとかもあるんで。
Also over there, we have fried chicken, cookies, and rice balls.
あ、いただきます！やったー！
Ah, let's eat! Yay!
座る、座る、座る、座って座る。ゆっくりしてください。
Sit down, sit down, sit down. Please make yourselves at home.
ありがとうございます。どうぞどうぞ。
Thank you. Please, go ahead.
びびちゃん、ここに来るたびにめっちゃいい匂いする。
Bibi-chan, every time I come here it smells so good.
おじさん！おじさんが来た！おじさん！
Old man! The old man is here! Old man!
おじさんじゃないです！食堂のおじさん。
I'm not an old man! The cafeteria old man.
このお店、裏で働いてる厨房のおじさんと、食堂のおじさんで...
This shop has an old man in the kitchen and an old man in the dining room...
いや、ちょっと、常連のおじさんですよ。常連のおじさん、ははは！
No, wait, I'm a regular customer old man. A regular old man, haha!
お酒飲んでる？べー先輩。飲んでない？
Are you drinking? Bae-senpai. Are you not?
飲んでない。もう疲れすぎてて。まるで酔っ払いになってる。
I'm not. I'm just so tired. I feel like a total drunk.
疲れすぎた。でも、あるんじゃないですか？
So tired. But, it happens, doesn't it?
たまに、なんか疲れが溜まりすぎて、まるで酔ってる気分。
Sometimes when exhaustion builds up, you feel like you're drunk.
心配だよ。休んでね。休みます。
I'm worried. Please rest. I will.
休んで。いける？え、いただきます！
Rest up. You okay? Oh, let's eat!
おでんいただきます。嬉しい。
I'll have some oden. I'm so happy.
今日、何にも食べてなかったから。
I haven't eaten anything today.
みんな、ちょっと。こっちが心配なんですけど！みんな食べてくださいよ。
Everyone, wait. I'm worried now! Please, everyone eat.
え、じゃあ、一番のおすすめ、このはんぺんをいただきます。
Then, I'll have the most recommended item, this hanpen.
はんぺん。初はんぺん。
Hanpen. My first hanpen.
うーん、やわらかい！
Mmm, it's so soft!
しもしもです、出汁が効いてる。
It's so soaked, the broth is really coming through.
やっぱみんなはんぺん好きだね。はんぺん美味しい。
As expected, everyone loves hanpen. It's delicious.
はんぺん、まつり先輩が描いてくれた。
Matsuri-senpai drew this hanpen.
びびのイラスト、めっちゃ可愛い。私が、私が今日...
The Bibi illustration is so cute. I, I today...
良くないですよ、みんな。もっとちゃんと食べてください。
It's not good, everyone. You need to eat more properly.
はい！可愛い。イラストレーター...
Yes! So cute. The illustrator...
食堂のおばさん？コップにわかりやすく描いてある。
The cafeteria lady? It's clearly drawn on the cup.
ありがとうございます。じゃあ、あずちゃんのもね。
Thank you. And here is AZ-chan's too.
あずちゃんのは、こんな感じです。
AZ-chan's is like this.
可愛い！まつりがおでん描いたの、ありがとうございます。
Cute! Matsuri drew the oden, thank you so much.
可愛すぎる。間違いない。知らないところで違うサービス始まってた。
Too cute. For sure. A different service had started without me knowing.
いろんなサービス。いろんなサービスがある。ありがとうございます。
Various services. There are all kinds of services. Thank you.
え、待って、あのデカすぎるタッパーに詰めてきた唐揚げ...
Wait, that fried chicken packed in that huge Tupperware...
空きが見える。半分減ってる。食べて食べて。
I can see the bottom. Half of it is gone. Eat, eat.
食べます！任せろ。すごい。
We'll eat! Leave it to us. Amazing.
でも入れ物もない。あ、向こうにもうなくなった、ひょっとして。
But there are no containers. Oh, are they already gone over there?
お、こっちはね、これはクッキー入ってたやつだし。
Oh, this one, this is what the cookies were in.
あとは多分こっちかな、あと二枚？唐揚げ。
The rest is probably over here, two more left? Fried chicken.
唐揚げじゃあもらいます。そのあとめちゃくちゃ食べていい？
I'll take some fried chicken. Can I eat a ton of it after?
これね。取り分け、取り分け。はい。
Here it is. Serving, serving. Yes.
え、じゃあお皿あるって。お皿あります、お皿。いいですか？
Oh, then we have plates. There are plates, plates. Is it okay?
全然、あ、あるから大丈夫。マネちゃんに。
Totally, oh, we have some so it's fine. Give some to Mane-chan.
マネちゃん、白いやつも持ってきて。私もこれ唐揚げ使ったので。
Mane-chan, bring the white one too. I used this for the fried chicken.
あ、いいですよ。いいよ。美味しい。幸せだ。
Ah, okay. It's fine. Delicious. I'm so happy.
じゃあお弁当の、お弁当の唐揚げいただきます。
Then, I'll have the lunch box fried chicken.
マネちゃん、うわ、デカい、デカい。デカいね。
Mane-chan, whoa, it's huge, huge. It really is.
お持ち帰りじゃない？お持ち帰りだよ。はい、もらった。
Isn't it for takeout? It is. Here, I got some.
唐揚げやったー。すごい、なくなることってあるんだ。
Fried chicken, yay! Wow, I didn't think it would actually run out.
みんなってお腹空いてる。みんなお腹空いてる。お腹空いてる。
Everyone is hungry. Everyone's hungry. Hungry.
美味しい。唐揚げ美味しい。やったー。ジューシー。
Delicious. Fried chicken is delicious. Yay! Juicy.
こんなにカリカリに揚げれるんや、家で。お店みたいなカリカリさ。
You can fry it to be this crispy at home. It's crispy just like a shop's.
ごちそうさまでした。お邪魔しました。
Thank you for the meal. Thank you for having us.
うわっ！
Whoa!
ごちそうさまです！
Thank you for the meal!
はーい。
Yes.
もう完食！
We finished everything!
完食！
Finished!
いっぱい食べてくれて...
Thank you for eating so much...
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
最高すぎる。
It was just too good.
ね。
Right.
マジで最高すぎる。
Seriously, it was the best.
あ、デザートのクッキー...
Ah, the dessert cookies...
クッキー！
Cookies!
クッキーまだありますね。
There are still some cookies left.
デザートね！
Dessert, right!
そっちの状況見てないんですけど...
I haven't seen the situation over there...
クッキー全部開けきりました。
I've opened all the cookies.
クッキーの女王...
The Cookie Queen...
あのクッキー食べた？
Did you eat those cookies?
いや、でもまだここにあるのと...
No, but there's still some here and...
まつりが持って帰る。
Matsuri is taking some home.
持って帰る！
Taking it home!
めちゃくちゃ好きやん。
She really loves them.
大好きなんだ。
She loves them.
かわいい〜
So cute.
一人とおにぎりと...
By herself, with an onigiri...
おにぎりも持って帰ってくれて...
She's taking onigiri home, too...
初めて梅干し食べるから...
Because it's her first time eating umeboshi...
梅干し初めて！
First time eating umeboshi!
初めて梅干し。
First time umeboshi.
すげー。
Amazing.
え、じゃあ食べたことある？
Eh, then have you eaten it before?
ある。ある。
Yes. Yes.
苦手な人は苦手ですよね、梅干し。
Some people really can't stand umeboshi, right?
ですよね。
Right.
食べれ... 苦手？梅干し。
Can you eat... do you dislike it? Umeboshi.
ん？好き。
Hm? I like it.
梅干し好きだった！
She liked umeboshi!
好きー。
I like it.
え、でも梅干し食べたことある？
Wait, but have you eaten umeboshi before?
ないかも...
Maybe not...
酸っぱいの食べれますか？
Can you eat sour things?
うん、食べれる。
Yeah, I can.
かわいい〜
So cute.
おにぎりよかったら...
If you'd like an onigiri...
おにぎりも持って帰って...
Take an onigiri home, too...
美味しいおにぎり。これ梅干し。
A delicious onigiri. This is umeboshi.
梅干し作ったんだって。
I heard she made the umeboshi.
梅干しだけ？
Just the umeboshi?
ここで漬けてきたやつ。
The ones she pickled here.
あ、作ったの？梅干し。
Ah, did she make them? The umeboshi.
おう！
Oh!
自分で？
By herself?
うん、漬けて... 美味しかった。
Yeah, pickled... it was delicious.
え、じゃあ一個もらっていいですか？
Eh, then can I have one?
明日の朝ごはん。
For tomorrow's breakfast.
クッキー... いいんですか？
Cookies... is it okay?
うわ、朝ごはん。
Wow, breakfast.
じゃあもらいます。
Then I'll take it.
クッキーもらってもいい？
Can I have a cookie, too?
あ、もちろん、もちろん。
Ah, of course, of course.
え、最高。
Eh, amazing.
もちろんって言ってまつりの...
Saying 'of course' but it's Matsuri's...
もうテーブル動かしてくれている方...
The person moving the table for us...
任せたな。
I've left it to them.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
うん！おふぉさん食べれ... 美味しい！
Yeah! This is edible... it's delicious!
美味しい、美味しい！
Delicious, delicious!
全部食べちゃうんじゃないかな。
I think I might eat it all.
すごい美味しかった。
It was so delicious.
あ、酸っぱい。
Ah, sour.
お腹いっぱい。
I'm full.
キャベツも美味しかった。
The cabbage was also delicious.
嬉しい〜
I'm so glad.
食べてくれました。
They ate it all.
よかった〜 美味しかった。
Great. It was delicious.
待って、クッキーが美味しすぎる。
Wait, the cookies are too delicious.
そうだよね！
I know, right!
ござるのクッキー大好きです。郷愁です。ごめんなさい。
I love Gozaru's cookies. It's nostalgic. Sorry.
流石... じゃあ朝から頑張らせていただきました。
As expected... Well, I've been working hard since morning.
あ、職人の朝は早いですね。
Ah, the craftsman's morning starts early.
あ、AZKiちが寝ている間にこねました。
Ah, I kneaded them while AZKi-chi was sleeping.
吹いた。こねてくれてました。
I laughed. She was kneading them.
クッキーの匂いでAZKiちが起きました。
AZKi-chi woke up to the smell of cookies.
最高な幸せな目覚めや。
It's the best, happiest awakening.
それがいいんだ。
That's what's good about it.
最高だな。持って帰ってもいいですか？
It's the best. Can I take some home?
いいよ。
Sure.
え、ふわもこ... え、Expoのござるクッキーもまだあります？
Eh, FuwaMoco... eh, are there still Gozaru cookies from Expo?
まだある！まだ大丈夫。食べて！
Still have them! They're still good. Eat them!
僕もまだあります。食べて！
I still have some, too. Eat them!
そうだから、ちょっと横に... ござるクッキーも... Expoのござるクッキーも置きたいですね。
So, I want to set some aside... Gozaru cookies... and the Expo Gozaru cookies, too.
クリームはないかな？
No cream, I guess?
去っちゃう。賞味期限...
It'll go bad. The expiration date...
ほんまや賞味期限。
Really, the expiration date.
感じてくれ。
Just feel it.
あ、それも食べ... 食べちゃあかんやつ。
Ah, that's something you... shouldn't eat.
そう、食べちゃダメだと思う。賞味期限切れてる。
Yeah, I think you shouldn't eat it. It's past its expiration date.
あ、クッキーってだってバターとか入ってるからさ。
Ah, because cookies have butter and stuff in them.
そっかそっか。卵とか。
I see, I see. Eggs and stuff.
去年の...
From last year...
去年？全然... あ、飴ちゃんっぽいクッキー。
Last year? Not at all... ah, candy-like cookies.
一口で...
In one bite...
息止まる？
Stop breathing?
息止まる？どこまで勝ってるかわからない。
Stop breathing? I don't know how far it goes.
あ、モコ... まだ... クッキー食べようよ〜
Ah, Moco... still... let's eat some cookies!
大事にね。観賞用なんですよね。
Be careful. They're for display, right?
そうです。大事なクッキーで。
That's right. They're precious cookies.
え、フワワもまつりに残しておきたい。
Eh, Fuwawa wants to leave some for Matsuri, too.
年中... 一昨年だよ。
All year round... it was the year before last.
え、ござるのクッキー... あの... あれね？いつでも言われたら作るから。
Eh, Gozaru's cookies... that... right? I'll make them whenever you ask.
ええ〜！食べて〜！ありがとう〜！
Whoa! Eat up! Thank you!
え、じゃあ一個... ちょっと置いとってください。
Eh, then one... please set one aside.
どうかな？
I wonder?
観賞用って... レジに出たよとか言われてる。
Display use... it's like what's at the register.
食べちゃうんです？
Are you going to eat it?
それだったらいいのか。
In that case, is it okay?
じゃあいいのかな？
Then maybe it's fine?
どうなんだろう。
I wonder.
でもよかった。永久保存版。
But it was good. A version for permanent preservation.
作ってきた甲斐が... 最高。
It was worth making them... the best.
美味しい。
Delicious.
最高。すっくりでいい？
The best. Is crispy okay?
ありがとう。なんかいろいろ持ってきてくれた。
Thank you. You brought all sorts of things.
これ？あ、そうそう。それにも持って帰りたいものがあれば...
This? Ah, right. If there's anything else you want to take home in that...
唐揚げとか詰めて...
Pack some karaage and...
お弁当！
A lunch box!
お弁当！お弁当箱みたいなやつ。
A lunch box! Like a lunch box thing.
お弁当箱。
Lunch box.
これね。これね。持って帰ってやるぜ。
This one. This one. I'll take it home.
生き生きとまつり先輩が...
Matsuri-senpai is so lively...
僕はこれだけで... ありがとうございます。
I'm fine with just this... Thank you very much.
おにぎりだけ？
Only the onigiri?
いやいやよかったよかった。
No, no, it's fine, it's fine.
おにぎりね、実は予定になかったんだけど。
The onigiri, actually, weren't in the plan.
あ、そうなんだ！
Ah, really!
AZKiちが... 酸っぱいから... おかずが多いから... ご飯も欲しいかなって。
AZKi-chi... because it's sour... and there are many side dishes... I thought they might want rice too.
そっかそっか。
I see, I see.
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
ね、優しい。
Yes, so kind.
本当に、遅くに来て申し訳なさすぎる。
Really, I'm so sorry for coming so late.
でも、可愛くなって、まだ仕事あります。
But, I still have work after this.
ええー？！
Ehhh?!
大丈夫です、大丈夫です。すみません。
It's okay, it's okay. Sorry.
ちょっと、ね。
Just, a bit.
頑張って！
Good luck!
常連のおじさんがちょっと失礼します。
A regular customer (old man) is leaving.
ね、みんな自撮りして。
Everyone's taking selfies.
わざわざ時間さいて。
Everyone came and spent time here.
夜中だし。
It's late.
ちょっと元気をチャージしてもらって。
I hope you charged up some energy.
お邪魔しました。
I'll be going now.
あ、自撮りしてる。
Oh, taking a selfie.
かわいい！
So cute!
僕も撮ろう。
I'll take one too.
本当にかわいいから。
Because it's really cute.
みんな自撮りして。
Everyone taking selfies.
自撮りだと思ったら違かった。
I thought it was a selfie, but it wasn't.
本当は動画ね。
Actually, it was a video.
自撮りだわ。
It's a selfie.
なるほどです。
I see.
べー。
Beh!
ロールキャベツとべー。
Roll cabbage and Beh!
うまー。
Delicious!
なんか、本当はロールキャベツ苦手やったんです。
Actually, I used to dislike roll cabbage.
え、そうなの？
Eh, really?
でも、食べたらおいしくて食べれるようになったかも。
But after eating this, I might be able to eat it now!
うれしー。
I'm so happy.
おいしい。
Delicious.
おめでとう。
Congratulations.
やっぱおでんのね、出汁もきいて。
The dashi in the oden is really working.
おいしくなってる。
It's so good.
はい、ほろほろ。
Yes, so tender.
ほろほろになってました。
It was so tender.
いや、それうれしすぎるな。
I'm so happy to hear that.
ね。おいしすぎた。
Right. It was too delicious.
おじ！
Oji!
おじが帰る。
Oji is leaving.
気を付けて。
Take care.
お出かけ。
He's going out.
仕事頑張って。
Good luck with work.
バイバーイ。
Bye-bye!
お疲れ様でした。
Thank you for your hard work.
頑張って。
Good luck.
忙しい。
She's busy.
いい香り。
She smells good.
私、朝からラジオの食べ物しか食べてないから。
I've only eaten radio food since morning.
だいぶなくなった。
It's almost all gone.
え、なくない？
Eh, there's none left?
え、なくなくない？
Eh, isn't it all gone?
なくなっちゃった？
Is it all gone?
あ、あげないからね。
Ah, I won't give it to you!
大事に。
Carefully.
そうだよ、大事に持って帰る。
That's right, I'll take it home carefully.
大事に持って帰るんだよ。
Take it home carefully.
大事に持って帰る。
I'll take it home carefully.
お持ち帰り。
Taking it home.
うますぎる。
It's too good.
逆にでもいいかも。
Actually, it might be fine the other way.
これだけ残して次これ持って帰る。
I'll leave this and take that home next time.
逆でもいいよ、やばい。
The other way is fine too, oh my god.
入れ物ごと。
Including the container.
スタッフが泣きそう。
The staff might cry.
あ、そっか。なくなる。
Ah, I see. It'll be gone.
それは後で程々に食べてもらってね。
Please let them eat some of it later.
大丈夫、大丈夫。
It's okay, it's okay.
助かりますから。
It helps.
でもまじでもうこんなになくなるとは。
But really, I didn't think it'd be this gone.
いっぱい作ってきた甲斐があります。
It was worth making so much.
おにぎりもらっていいですか？
Can I have an onigiri?
え、あ、はい。
Eh, oh, sure.
梅干し。
Umeboshi.
今食べたい？
You want to eat it now?
え、今食べたい。
Yes, I want to eat it now.
チンとかする？
Should I microwave it?
行ったらチンとかしてくれて。
If you go, they'll microwave it for you.
いや、おにぎり大丈夫。
No, the onigiri is fine.
うわ、おいしそう。
Wow, looks delicious.
すごい。食べたかった。
Amazing. I wanted to eat this.
食べる。
I'll eat it.
梅干し。
Umeboshi.
ドキドキ。
Heart pounding.
五臓六腑に。
To the internal organs...
五臓六腑に染み渡るよ。
It's soaking into my soul.
食レポが。
The taste report...
ちなみに米と海苔はスポンサーは風真家。
By the way, the rice and seaweed are sponsored by the Kazama family.
風真家の。
From the Kazama family.
はい、から届いたね。
Yes, it arrived from there.
近所さん諸々からいただいた。
We received it from various neighbors.
豪華。
How luxurious.
いただきます。
I'll have some!
海苔、海苔。
Seaweed, seaweed.
ビビたんが。
Bibi-tan.
んー！梅干しまでたどり着いた？
Mmm! Reached the umeboshi?
んめ、めっちゃ梅干し。
Yum, it's very umeboshi.
めっちゃおいしい。
It's so delicious.
かなりちゃんと酸味がある。
It has a pretty good sourness.
あ、結構酸っぱい。
Oh, it's quite sour.
うん、おにぎりとかお粥用。
Yes, it's for onigiri or okayu.
結構酸っぱめのおいしい。
It's a nice, sharp sourness.
しそもちゃんと聞いてて。
The shiso is also distinct.
あ、よかった。
Oh, I'm glad.
ご馳走です。
It's a feast.
そうですよね。
That's right.
よくわかりましたね、グルメ。
You figured it out, gourmet.
酸っぱいの好きやからちょうどいい酸っぱさ。
I like sour things, so it's the perfect sourness.
おいしー。
So good.
ゼータ先輩。
Zeta-senpai.
食べよう。
Let's eat.
初梅干しか？
Her first umeboshi?
まつりも初梅干し、今食べて。
Matsuri is also having her first umeboshi now.
初めて食べる？初めて。
Eating for the first time? Ever?
梅干し？
Umeboshi?
わかる。初めてやからずっと記憶に残るよ。
I get it. Since it's your first, it'll stay in your memory.
乾杯してる。
They're doing a toast.
おにぎりで乾杯してる。
Toasting with onigiri.
大丈夫だった？
Were you okay?
あ、梅干しいけなかった。
Ah, couldn't handle the umeboshi.
お米とでした。
It was just the rice.
どうですか？酸っぱい？
How is it? Is it sour?
かなり！
Extremely!
でも、うまい。
But it's good.
よかった。
I'm glad.
あの、里の人間も喜びます。
The people of the village will be happy too.
お米と海苔とね。
With the rice and seaweed.
うちのスポンサーの方々が喜びます。
Our sponsors will be happy.
まつり先輩。
Matsuri-senpai.
おいしい。
It's delicious.
え、大丈夫？
Eh, are you okay?
大丈夫。おいしい。
I'm okay. It's delicious.
ちなみにまつり、しそもダメだったんだけど。
By the way, Matsuri used to be bad with shiso too.
おいしい、これ。
This is delicious.
あー、よかった。
Ah, I'm glad.
今日だけで苦手を克服していく。
Overcoming weaknesses today!
ほんとだ。
That's true.
くさみたいなのはね...
Something like herbs...
...うつっちゃってる気がするんです。
...I feel like they're reflected.
梅の方に全て。そうしそ、しそで漬けてたの。
Everything's on the plum. Yes, they were pickled with shiso.
美味しい！美味しい！
Delicious! Delicious!
なんかおにぎり久しぶりに食べました、手作りの。
It's been a while since I had onigiri. Homemade ones.
確かに。
True.
暖かさを感じる。嬉しい。
I can feel the warmth. I'm happy.
確かに。
True.
事の発端は本当は今日来たかったスバル先輩が、
It all started because Subaru-senpai, who actually wanted to come today,
昔、昔でもないな、
back then... well, not that long ago,
ああ、数ヶ月前か。
Ah, a few months ago.
数ヶ月前か、なんか死にそうになってた時に、
a few months ago, when she felt like she was dying,
ごはんとおにぎりを持ってった時に、
when I brought her rice and onigiri,
「千と千尋のハクのおにぎりみたいにうめー！」ってなってて。
she said, "This is as delicious as Haku's onigiri from Spirited Away!"
泣きながら、ボロボロ...
Crying, with tears streaming down...
そう。スバル先輩がじゃあ今日来るんだったら持ってくかーって。
Yeah. So we thought if Subaru-senpai was coming today, we'd bring some.
そう、それもあって、ゆで、事始まったんだよね。
Yeah, that's also why this whole thing started.
そうそうそう。届けに行きますからねスバル先輩って言って。
Exactly. We said, "We'll go deliver them to you, Subaru-senpai."
呼んでくださいねってちょっとこれ、来れなくなっちゃって。
We told her to call us, but she couldn't make it.
うん。そう、そんなことも思いながらいろいろ作って。
Yeah. So we made various things while thinking about that.
わかるわ、その泣き出すスバル先輩の気持ちが。
I understand how the crying Subaru-senpai felt.
愛を感じたんです。
She must have felt the love.
愛を。
The love.
おにぎり... あったかいよ。
Onigiri... It's warm.
美味しい！
Delicious!
よかった。
I'm glad.
なかなか作ることないから。
Since I don't usually have a chance to make them.
ああ、やっぱりね。普段おにぎりは作る？
Ah, I see. Do you usually make onigiri?
作らないですよね。
We don't, do we?
形でなんか、全部詰めて形でポンって...
With a mold, putting everything in and popping it out...
あるあるある！
I know, I know!
そう、だけどなんか上手くできてない気が...
Yeah, but I feel like I'm not doing it very well...
ねー。なるほどね。ござるんちのおにぎりの作り方、特殊だから。
Right. I see. Because the way the Gozaru household makes onigiri is special.
今度教わろう。教わったんですけど。
I'll teach you next time. Well, I already taught you.
へー。
Oh.
ござるんちはかなり特殊なおにぎりの作り方。
The Gozaru household has quite a special way of making onigiri.
気になる！
I'm curious!
ラップばーって敷いて。はい。
Lay out the plastic wrap like this. Yes.
3個ぐらい海苔と、海苔間隔で敷いて。
Lay out three pieces of seaweed with a certain spacing.
上にごはん乗っけて。ラップこう間、こうぱーって切って。
Put rice on top. Then cut the wrap in between like this.
ラップを間で切る。
Cut the wrap in between.
おお〜、効率よさそう！
Oh, looks efficient!
そう、包んで。
Yeah, then wrap them.
俵にしてから台形にして、終わり。
Shape them into cylinders, then into trapezoids, and done.
俵、俵系の...
Cylinder, cylinder-style...
...おにぎりでした。
...onigiri, it was.
あ、じゃあちょっと先輩、1個おにぎり取ってもらっていいですか？
Ah, senior, could you take one onigiri for me?
そっか、それ見せたい。
Right, I want to show that.
そう。1回ここに出すんで。
Yeah. I'll put it out here for now.
取られるかと思った。
I thought it was going to be taken.
取られる嫌だね、食べてる時。
It's bad to have it taken while you're eating.
ちょっとあの、普通に皆さんすみません、あのよくあるお弁当おにぎりみたいで申し訳ないんですけど。
Sorry everyone, it's just a common lunchbox onigiri, but...
お弁当おにぎりね。
A lunchbox onigiri.
ちょっと台形の... うちは台形になりがちです。
A bit of a trapezoid... Ours tend to be trapezoids.
天むすとか挿す時、上からグサリといけますから。ここから。
When you stick in things like tenmusu, you can go right in from the top. Like this.
おお〜。天むす作れるの？
Oh. You can make tenmusu?
天むすは作れます！
I can make tenmusu!
あ、天むす、いいー！
Oh, tenmusu is great!
作ってほしそうな顔！
You look like you want me to make some!
でも天むすにはうるさいよ、愛知だから。
But I'm picky about tenmusu since I'm from Aichi.
そうだ、愛知だから！
That's right, because you're from Aichi!
そっか、確かに。
Right, true.
天むすの...
The tenmusu...
じゃあうちのスポンサーの方々に、ちょっとまた材料提供して...
Then I'll ask our sponsors to provide materials again...
エビ、エビの提供。
...shrimp, a supply of shrimp.
エビ何かなりませんかね。エビ。いいエビ。
Can't we do something about the shrimp? Shrimp. Good shrimp.
食べたくなるって。
It makes me want to eat it.
エビ業、ちょっと仕入れないといけない。
I'll have to source some from the shrimp industry.
やった！その時また開いてください、食堂。
Yay! Please open the diner again then.
来ます。常連になるから。
I'll come. I'll become a regular.
常連嬉しい、ありがとう。
I'm happy for regulars, thank you.
本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
なんか来てくれるからね。本当に嬉しいです。
Because you guys come. I'm really happy.
すみません、何も持ってきてない、胃袋だけ持ってきました。
Sorry, I didn't bring anything, just my stomach...
おめでとうございます！
Congratulations!
いや胃袋どうやって置いてくるんだよ、って突っ込んであげてよ。
Someone call her out on how she'd even leave her stomach behind.
胃袋空じゃない。
Not an empty stomach.
胃袋どうやって持ってくる...
How do you bring your stomach...
常連になってやつをやっぱりやります。
I'll definitely do the regular customer thing.
そうですね。次回、何がいいですかね？
Right. What would be good for next time?
次回何がいい？
What would be good next time?
フワちゃんとか、モコちゃん、食べたいものありますか？
Fuwa-chan or Moco-chan, is there anything you want to eat?
フワ先輩、何が好きですか？
Fuwa-senpai, what do you like?
何でも好きなんだけど。
I like everything, but...
え〜、何... 何だろうね。
Hmm, what... I wonder what.
フワちゃん、もし作ってほしい...
Fuwa-chan, if you want something made...
え〜、でもここってなんかみんなで食べれるのがいいですもんね。
Hmm, but here, it's nice to have something everyone can eat together.
シェアできる。
Something we can share.
確かに。重ならない。
True. Not overlapping.
何やろうなあ。
I wonder what.
何やろうなあ、でも関西で言うと、たこ焼きとか。
I wonder. But speaking of Kansai, things like takoyaki.
わー、楽しそう！
Oh, that looks fun!
ちょっと火が使えないから難しい。
It's a bit difficult because we can't use fire.
ホットプレートもダメなん？
Is a hot plate also no good?
ホットプレート湯気が出ちゃう...
A hot plate will produce steam...
湯気じゃなくて煙が出ちゃうんだっけ？
Not steam, was it smoke?
もう作ってあるやつをみんなで囲うとか。
Maybe we can just gather around something already made.
みんなでもう大量に作って。
Make a huge batch together.
で、なんかちょっとロシアンルーレットでなんかチョコ入れたり。
And maybe some Russian Roulette with chocolate inside.
わさびとか。
Or wasabi.
わさび！
Wasabi!
なんか始まるぞ。
Something's starting.
100個ぐらいじゃあ並べて。
Let's line up about a hundred of them.
いいですね。
That sounds good.
えー、なんかクレープとか。
Hmm, how about crepes?
おおー！
Oh!
アドベントでクレープで配信やってたけど。
We did a crepe stream during Advent.
あー！
Ah!
納豆も入って...
There was even natto...
え、納豆クレープ！
Eh, natto crepes!
納豆クレープ！
Natto crepes!
フワちゃん、甘いものも入ってて。
Fuwa-chan, there were sweet things too.
あ、しょっぱいのも。納豆も入ってて。
Ah, and salty things too. Natto was also in it.
なんか難しかった。
It was kind of difficult.
べぶんちゃんもすごいことなってて。
Bebun-chan's was also in a crazy state.
トラウマだった。
It was a trauma.
トラウマ！
Trauma!
クレープでトラウマになっちゃった。
Crepes have become a trauma.
トラウマになっちゃった。
They've become a trauma.
みんな可愛いクレープ作って、フワちゃんにね、それを食べさせられた。
Everyone made cute crepes, and Fuwa-chan was made to eat them.
納豆とか...
Like natto...
（笑い声と重なり合う会話）
(Laughter and overlapping chatter)
でもクレープもいいですね。
But crepes are good too, aren't they?
梅干しクレープとか、酸っぱいクレープもいいな。
Like umeboshi crepes... Sour crepes would be good too.
おお、クレープ。美味しい。
Oh, crepes. Delicious.
AZKi先輩はさっき天むすって...
AZKi-senpai, you said tenmusu earlier...
天むす食べたい！何でも食うよ！
I want to eat tenmusu! I'll eat anything!
何でも！そうですよね、何でも！
Anything! That's right, anything!
野菜じゃなければ...
As long as it's not vegetables...
ワッフルとか！ワッフルね！
Like waffles! Waffles, right!
それやりたいなー。
I want to do that.
お二人の得意料理って何なんですか？
What are your specialty dishes?
何だろう...満遍なく何でも一応作るけど...
I wonder... I generally make a bit of everything, but...
さすが！かっこいい！
As expected! So cool!
ござる、ぶっちゃけ料理よりお菓子...
Iroha, to be honest, I'm better at sweets than cooking...
あ、お菓子か！
Ah, sweets!
料理も...卵系かな...
As for cooking... maybe egg-based dishes...
卵系？出し巻きとか？
Egg-based? Like dashimaki?
オムライスとか！
Like omurice!
え、オムライス食べたい！オムライスいい！
Eh, I want to eat omurice! Omurice is great!
オムライス食べたい！
I want to eat omurice!
オムライス結構好きなメンバー...
There are many members who like omurice...
あ、さっき好きって言ってましたよね。
Ah, you were saying you liked it earlier.
あ、ラプラスがね。
Ah, La+ does.
うちは総帥にキッズ飼ってるから...
Since I'm keeping the leader as a kid...
キッズがオムライス食べたいって定期的連絡来る。
I get messages regularly saying the kids want omurice.
あずいろ食堂なんで、和食の大皿のメニューとかを...
Since it's Azuiro Diner, maybe a large platter of Japanese dishes...
いっぱい置いてみんなにバイキングで...
Put out a lot of food and let everyone have it buffet-style...
わあ、最高！
Wow, that's the best!
仕込みが大変なことになりそう...
The prep work is going to be a lot of trouble...
それやりたい！
I want to do that!
食堂でめっちゃいっぱい作ってあって、みんな自分で取ってくあれ...
Having a lot of dishes in the diner and everyone picking what they want...
主菜と副菜こう並べて...
Lining up main and side dishes...
もう本業にしたほうがいいぐらいですね、レベルが...
The level is high enough that it could be a main job...
お金取ったほうがいいよ、ここ。やる時。払いますよ、みんな！
You should charge money here when you do it. Everyone will pay!
お金取ったほうがいい！
You should definitely charge money!
そんなことあります？
Is that so?
皆が美味しく食べてくれるのが我々もあり甲斐がありますから。
Having everyone eat delicious food is rewarding for us too.
後片付け係なんで。やりましょうまたね！
I'm the cleanup crew. Let's do it again!
またぜひ！はい！
Definitely again! Yes!
じゃあアンケート取るか、食べたい...
Then let's take a survey on what people want to eat...
あ、そうだね。食べたいおかず二つぐらい募集して...
Ah, that's right. Collect about two dishes people want to eat...
ランキング戦にして...
Make it a ranking...
みんなのチャンネルでね。
On everyone's channel.
配信で発表して、5位の中で人気だったおかず...
Announce it on stream, the popular dishes among the top 5...
あと料理作りたいっていう...
And people who want to help cook...
いいな！作りたい！やりましょう！
Sounds good! I want to cook! Let's do it!
お餅作ったりとかもしたい。
I also want to make mochi or something.
何でも作りたいです！
I want to make anything!
AZKi先輩とイロハ先輩と一緒に...
Together with AZKi-senpai and Iroha-senpai...
何でもって言ったな？よし、揚げたドーナツ作るぞ！
You said anything, right? Alright, we're making fried donuts!
油怖いけど頑張るよ！
Oil is scary, but I'll do my best!
ということで、なんと、もうここで...
And with that, surprisingly, it's already...
そろそろ閉店のお時間...
Time for closing...
えー！
Eh?!
おでんの方は全然ゆっくり食べて頂いて...
Please feel free to take your time with the oden...
受付が締め切りな感じなんで...
The reception is closing up...
今日はあずいろ食堂開店ということで...
Since today was the opening of Azuiro Diner...
いっぱいフラスタも頂いたり...
We received a lot of flower stands...
フラスタ本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for the flower stands!
みんなもたくさん来ていただきましてありがとうございました！
Thank you to everyone who came today!
ふわもこちゃんも！
Fuwamoco-chan too!
バウバウ！ありがとうございました！
Bau bau! Thank you very much!
来たかったけど来れなかったよっていうホロメンからのメッセージとかも色々頂いてて...
We received messages from Hololive members who wanted to come but couldn't...
またね、次回のどこかでやれたらいいなと思ってます！
I hope we can do this again sometime in the future!
ホロメンが胃袋を持って食べに来てくれる限り続きます、この店は！
This shop will continue as long as Hololive members bring their appetites and come to eat!
やったー！絶対来ます！
Yay! We'll definitely come!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
配信見てくださってる方もありがとうございました！
Thank you to everyone watching the stream!
サンキュー！バウバウ！
Thank you! Bau bau!
みんなもおでん食べて体温めてくれよな！
Everyone, eat some oden and keep yourselves warm!
おでん！おでん！美味しいよ、おでん！
Oden! Oden! It's delicious, oden!
では最後にみんなでごちそうさまでした、を！
Now, finally, let's all say "Gochisousama deshita"!
はい！やりましょう！
Yes! Let's do it!
せーの！
One, two!
ごちそうさまでしたー！
Thank you for the meal!
めっちゃ美味しかった！
It was so delicious!
Please subscribe AZKi Channel / Follow me @AZKi_VDiVA
Please subscribe AZKi Channel
Follow me @AZKi_VDiVA